Bells will ring at the New York Stock Exchange
紐約證券交易所又迎來新的一天
for another day, on this March 18th.
今天是3月18日
Okay, here we go. Are you listening?
好了 開始 你聽到嗎?
Are you paying attention out there?
你專心聽了嗎?
Good. Because it's about to get complicated,
很好 因為接下來會很複雜
so I'm gonna start out slow and make it nice and simple for you.
那麼我就開始慢慢說 好讓你容易聽懂
You don't have a clue where your money is.
你一點兒都不知道自己的錢在哪
See, once upon a time,
很久很久以前
you could walk into your bank, and they'd open a vault
你可以到銀行去 他們會打開一個保險箱
and point to a gold brick.
給你看一塊金磚
Not anymore.
如今不是了
Your money, that thing that you bust your ass for,
你的錢 你為之拼命的錢
it's nothing more than a few photons of energy
不過是一些光子能
traveling through a massive network of fiber optic cables.
在巨大的光纖網路中穿梭
Why'd we do it?
為什麼會這樣?
We did it to make it go faster.
我們如此做是為了速度更快
Because your money better be fast.
因為你的錢最好快速移動
Faster than the other guy's.
比別人快
But if you want faster markets with faster trades,
但若你想要更快速的市場 更快速的交易
faster profits, faster everything,
快速回報 一切都快速
sometimes you're gonna blow a tire.
有時就會爆胎
And that is exactly what happened yesterday
就像昨天東部標準時間下午1點07分
at 1:07 p.m., Eastern Standard Time.
發生的事情一樣
(沃夫佈雷澤 新聞直播間)
After heavy after-hours trading, Ibis's stock price took an historic $67...
經歷過大量市後交易 埃比斯股票達到歷史新高67美元...
run by high-frequency trading pioneer Walt Camby,
由高交易率先鋒華特·坎比當家
(埃比斯首席行政長官華特·坎比找藉口)
disclosed that an algorithm managing its portfolio suddenly went haywire.
說管理公司投資組合的演算法突然失控
The trading algorithm seems to have experienced an unexplained anomaly.
交易演算法似乎出現無法解釋的不規則計算
A glitch.
故障
Shares of Ibis Clear Capital getting killed this morning.
埃比斯金融公司股票今天上午大幅下跌
net loss of over $800 million.
淨損失超過八億美金
- It has gone haywire.  - An algorithm...
- 已經失控了  - 演算法...
- glitch...  - ...a glitch...
- 故障...  - 故障...
- glitch!  - A glitch.
- 故障  - 是故障
Okay, so Ibis took a beating yesterday,
好吧 埃比斯昨天損失慘重
but if you've been paying attention to me for the past 16 months,
但若你在這16個月來一直認真聽我說
Walt Camby has made you a lot of money.
華特·坎比已經讓你掙了好多錢
(埃比斯)
But if you were late to the party, I'm not going to sugarcoat it,
若你遲到了 我不會說好聽的
you got your ass smacked yesterday.
你昨天狠狠挨了一頓揍
But this is only the first round. Because this, my friend, is an opportunity.
但這僅僅是第一局 因為這是個機會 我們朋友
So here's what you're gonna do.
所以你該這樣做
You're gonna stop whining, and you're gonna get back in the ring
不要再抱怨了 趕快回到賽場上去
because this stock is coming back.
因為股價會回升的
You know what that means?
知道什麼意思嗎?
Let's go throw some punches.
讓我們來打幾拳
My money ain't funny and it keep comin' I welcome the money and the cash
我的錢不好笑 一直上漲 我歡迎財源滾滾來
金錢怪獸
What do you mean he's ordained?
什麼叫他受戒了?
No, on a plane, Lee. A plane.
不是 是坐飛機 利 飛機
All right. That makes more sense.
這就說得通了
Wait, Walt Camby's on a plane?
等等 華特·坎比在飛機上?
Can you pick up the pace, please? It's like dealing with my grandmother.
麻煩你能跟上我嗎? 好像我在跟老祖母說話似的
Come on, I'm not having a conversation with you through the goddamn door.
拜託 我不想跟你隔著門說話
All right, I'll leave it open next time.
好吧 我下次會開著門
Wait, now, why the hell would Walt cancel? He called me from Geneva yesterday.
等等 華特為什麼取消? 他昨天從日內瓦給我打電話
I don't know. He's on a plane.
我不知道 他在飛機上
And how are we just finding out about it now?
我們怎麼現在才發現呢?
That is a great question.
這問題好
You can ask him the next time you talk to him.
你下次跟他聊天時可以問他
Here. First one's a yes. Second one's a no.
你看這 第一個填"是" 第二個"否"
Third one's just a signature.
第三個簽字
- Ten minutes, Mr. Gates.  - All right.
- 還有10分鐘 蓋茲先生  - 好
- Thanks, Gen.  - Yep.
- 謝了 吉納  - 不用謝
The fill-in's name is Diane Lester. They're setting up her remote feed now.
取代他的是黛安·萊斯特 他們現在正準備她的遠端存取
- Who the hell is Diane Lester?  - She is the Chief Communications Officer.
- 黛安·萊斯特是誰?  - 是首席通訊長官
She wrote all the talking points anyway, so should be fine.
反正要點都是她寫的 所以應該沒問題
When am I getting the revisions for the opening?
我什麼能看到開場白修訂?
We're making some changes on it. Anybody seen Ron?
我們正在做改動 羅恩呢?
Might I get those before the show or after the show?
節目開始前還是結束後給我?
You know the drill. You just point the camera in my direction,
你把攝像機對準我就好
and we'll figure it out together.
我們會一起解決的
It always sounds so simple and yet so moronic.
總是聽起來很簡單 但實際上很蠢
All right. Look out, fellas. Here we come.
小心點 夥計們 這邊走
Edgar Rosenthal's office called.
愛德格羅森塔爾的辦公室打電話來
- He can't make dinner tonight.  - Thank Christ.
- 他今晚不能來赴宴了  - 謝天謝地
Dinner at the nursing home with my nan is more exciting than dinner with that guy.
就算在養老院跟我奶奶吃飯 都比跟他吃飯好玩
This is the 7th reschedule. So can I just move it to the TBD list?
這是他第七次改時間了 標記為"待定"好嗎?
Wait a minute, it's the 7th time he's rescheduled on me?
等等 他跟我約的時間改了七次?
Yes, that's correct.
對 沒錯
That's ridiculous. I'm calling him on his cell.
太荒唐了 我要打他手機
Well, his office said that he's in a meeting.
他的辦公室說他在開會
- Hey, Freddy, nice call on the yen yesterday.  - Eat a dick, Lee.
- 弗洛狄 昨天的日元報告不錯  - 去你的 利
Lee, this is Diane Lester.
利 這位是黛安·萊斯特
Alan, can you bring the boom in for me, please?
亞蘭 把話筒送進來
Ed! It's Lee Iacocca.
埃德 我是利·艾科卡
Listen, I changed my mind on this whole retirement thing.
聽著 關於退休的事 我徹底改變主意了
Turns out I want your job after all.
其實我想要你的工作
Yeah, it's Gates.
對 我是蓋茲
Okay. All right, I'll talk to you later.
好吧 回頭再說
All right.
好吧
So no dinner.
那麼沒晚飯了
Lee. Follow the noise. Diane Lester.
利 跟著我 黛安·萊斯特
- Memo of talking points.  - Hello? Hello?
- 採訪要點備忘錄  - 喂? 喂?
You guys at Ibis can't do anything right these days, can you?
我猜埃比斯最近幹什麼錯什麼 是吧?
Look, I'm really sorry to put you in this situation, Lee.
聽著 很抱歉讓你陷入這種境地
I fit was something we could control, believe me, we would.
如果我們能控制 我們會做的
I'm not the enemy here, Diane. I'm friendly fire.
我不是敵人 黛安 我是友善且公平的
We know that. If you read my talking points...
我們知道 若你看過我的要點...
Guy's a billionaire. He owns how many jets?
他是個億萬富翁 他有多少架私人飛機?
- Walt has already addressed the glitch...  - Five minutes!
- 我們會處理故障...  - 還有5分鐘
'Cause commercial flights, they get delayed,
因為商務航班經常晚點
but private ones, they get to do whatever the hell they want.
但是私人飛機 想去哪就去哪
- Ron! Where's Ron?  - I'm not sure. But here's a list of dinners...
- 羅恩 羅恩呢?  - 我不知道 但有晚宴...
We'll be with you in less than five, Diane.
我們不到5分鐘就會回來 黛安
Look at that. I wouldn't invite any of those people to an audit.
看看這個 我不會邀請他們任何人參加審計會
Ron!
羅恩
Ron. There you are. Is that my Canadian commodities data?
羅恩 你在這呀 這是我的加拿大貨品資料?
Yeah, yeah. Sorry.
對 抱歉
Sorry, I just ran all the way back from the Village.
抱歉 我剛從格林威治跑回來
I had a meeting with Tony Biscano at Licem Pharmaceutical.
我跟萊塞製藥廠的托尼·比斯卡諾開了個會
Lee, I'll be in your ear.
利 我跟你用耳麥聯繫
He gave me this.
他給我這個
- What is it?  - It's erectile cream.
- 這是什麼?  - 是勃起乳液
Tony Biscano of Licem gave you erectile cream?
萊塞製藥廠的托尼·比斯卡諾給你勃起乳液?
Yeah.
嗯
I guess I wasn't aware of the exact nature of your relationship.
我想我還真沒意識到 你們是這種關係
They've been testing this thing for over a year
他們已經做了很多年試驗
and the approval from the FDA finally came in last night.
食品藥品監察局 昨天晚上終於批准了
They're sending out a press release...
他們會發新聞通告...
- And it works?  - Apparently, yeah. Pretty damn well.
- 有效嗎?  - 當然 很有效
- Have you tried it?  - I just got it, 30 minutes ago.
- 你試過了?  - 剛試過
- What the hell are you waiting for?  - You want me to...
- 你還在等什麼?  - 你想我...
We're on in five minutes, aren't we? Put it on!
我們還有5分鐘就開播了 快加進來
Mr. Gates, you need this. Don't forget your talking points.
蓋茲先生 你需要這個 別忘了你的採訪要點
Yeah, yeah. Put it on my desk.
好 放到我桌子上
Okay, where is Diane Lester?
好吧 黛安·萊斯特在哪?
She's all checked in on remote six.
她在遠端六頻道等著呢
Who writes this shit?
這破玩意是誰寫的?
- Is the graphics package loaded?  - Last one is just coming in.
- 圖片都準備好了嗎?  - 最後一張剛弄好
Great.
很好
We are still working off the rehearsal script for the opening, guys.
我們還在修改開場白的彩排稿
But he didn't even stick to the rehearsal script at rehearsal.
他彩排都不按稿子說
- So, about dinner... Did you...  - Okay, you wore me down.
- 那麼 晚餐的事... 你...  - 好了 我沒耐心了
I'm sorry?
你說什麼?
I'll go to dinner with you. We'll go to Scalinatella's, let's say 9:30?
我會跟你吃飯 去薩卡裡娜塔莉吃 9點半行嗎?
I still have a boyfriend, Lee. Just like I did yesterday.
我還有男朋友呢 利 昨天有 今天也有
Yeah, he's still a bartender in Hoboken, like he was yesterday.
哦對 他是霍博肯的酒保 昨天是 今天也是
- Will this work, boss?  - This is a stuffed parrot.
- 這個行嗎 老闆?  - 這是個鸚鵡標本
I said I wanted a live pigeon.
我要的是活鴿子
Patty, God damn it.
帕蒂 該死的
We don't have a live pigeon.
我們沒有活鴿子
- Admit it. You're gonna miss this.  - You can't find a live pigeon?
- 承認吧 你會想念這份工作的  - 就找不到活鴿子嗎?
I'm sure there are plenty of emotionally stunted 7-year-olds
我敢肯定街對面有好多情感發育不良的7歲小孩
hosting TV shows across the street. Thank you.
在主持電視節目 謝謝啦
Cover yourself... Roll with yourself in breadcrumbs
你往自己... 身上撒滿麵包屑
and bring a fucking bird up here.
就能他媽的抓到只活鳥了
Jim, can you punch Diane up on the preview for me, please?
吉姆 給我切黛安的預覽畫面好嗎?
Sure. There she is.
好的 在這裡
Patty? Patty?
帕蒂? 帕蒂?
- Hi, Diane, can you hear me?  - Yes. Yes, I can.
- 黛安 能聽到嗎?  - 能聽到
Lee has read the talking points, right?
利看過要點了吧?
Because I'm in a tough position here,
因為我處境很艱難
and I just want to make sure that he sticks to the script.
我想確保他照著稿子來
He will. You know us, Diane. We don't do "gotcha" journalism here.
他會的 你瞭解我們 黛安 我們不會"出其不意"
Hell, we don't do journalism, period.
我們不是記者 就這樣
Scream one is up.
一號尖叫準備完畢
Check. Check. Check.
喂 喂 喂
Money... Money... Money Monster.
金錢... 金錢... 金錢怪獸
About time.
時間快到了
All right, I'm ready.
我準備好了
So, here's a novel idea.
給你個新點子
How about you just pick up some takeout on your way home.
你不如回家路上買個外賣吧
God, stop. I'm getting depressed.
天呐 別說了 我都抑鬱了
Get into your most comfortable pair of pajamas.
穿上你最舒服的睡褲
No, no, no. This isn't really a Friday night for you, is it? Can't be.
不 不 不 對你來說不是個週五晚上吧?
Curl right up in front of the TV?
蜷縮在電視機前如何?
It's 'cause the idea of television and pajamas and takeout, good God, it's like...
你這個穿睡褲 看電視 吃外賣的主意 我的天呐 就像...
You get a pool cue, and I want you to sharpen it down to a fine point.
拿個撞球杆 我想讓你好好推一杆
And I want you to shove it straight through my eye.
你就在我眼裡推
- Hold on a sec, Lee.  - Right into my brain.
- 等一下 利  - 一下推到我的腦子裡
You're killing me here, Lenny. Check your mark, please.
這不行 蘭尼 請檢查你的位置
You know what? I drifted and I forgot to lock.
你知道嗎? 我移了一下但忘了鎖定
Balls.
該死
That's it.
這下好多了
I would rather you do that than sitting at home in my underwear
我寧願你這樣 也不想穿著內褲坐在家裡
watching "Suck-My-QVC."
看"什麼鬼電視購物"
Look at the new guy.
來了個新人
Where's Leroy? Finally canned his ass.
裡洛伊呢? 他終於被炒魷魚了吧
One minute to air.
距直播一分鐘
One minute. Clear the stage, please.
一分鐘 請清場
Patty, honest answer.
帕蒂 你老實說
How many nights a week do you eat dinner in your pajamas?
你一周有多少天是穿睡衣吃晚餐的?
Like, on average, over the course of my life? Or just since James left?
平均來講 我這一輩子? 還是說詹姆斯之後?
Listen, listen.
聽著
Because I haven't eaten dinner alone since the '90s. That's hand to God.
我自從90年代起 就沒自己吃過晚餐 我對天發誓
Well, that's just awful. That just makes me feel sorry for you.
太糟了 我同情你
Why do you feel sorry for me?
你為什麼同情我?
Hang on, Patty. Just one second. Ron, you walking hard or what?
等等 帕蒂 羅恩 你勃起了還是怎樣?
This stuff is incredible.
這玩意難以置信
I'm talking zero to 60 in, like, 20 seconds flat.
就好像從起步到每小時60公里 只用20秒
Good, so it's a buy, then.
好 看來有用
All right. Put it away and find me a better lead for next week's show.
好了 收起來吧 然後給下周的節目找個好點子
Put it away?
收起來?
- Lee, necklace.  - Yeah. Okay. Thank you.
- 利 項鍊  - 是啊 好 謝謝
Thirty seconds till air. Thirty seconds.
30秒後開始直播 30秒
Where's my hat?
我的帽子呢?
Can we turn down the contrast on her a little bit, please?
她的畫面對比度調低些好嗎?
Sure.
好的
- How's that?  - That's better. Thank you.
- 怎麼樣?  - 好多了
- Fifteen seconds.  - Okay.
- 還有15秒  - 好
Here we go. Good luck, everybody.
開始了 祝各位好運
- Open on VT 16.  - Ten, nine...
- 16號視頻標題打開  - 十 九...
- Coming out of the opening to camera 3.  - ...eight, seven...
- 3號機開場  - 八 七...
Six,
六
five,
五
four,
四
three, two,
三 二
- one.  - Track rollup.
- 一  - 開播
(利·蓋茲 金錢怪獸)
Here he is, the wizard of Wall Street himself, Lee Gates.
有請華爾街魔法師利·蓋茲
My money ain't funny and it keep comin' I welcome the money and the cash
我的錢不好笑 一直上漲 我歡迎財源滾滾來
At the welcome mat swollen fat In stupid stacks, the cash
金銀財寶都滾到門口來
My money ain't funny and it keep comin'...
我的錢不好笑 一直上漲...
Thank you very much. The name is Lee Gates.
非常感謝 我是利·蓋茲
The show is Money Monster,
這裡是《金錢怪獸》
the day is Friday,
今天是星期五
and the Dow has dropped a seismic seven points this morning.
道鐘斯指數今早下跌七個百分點
Ready scream one.
一號尖叫準備
Should you...
你是否該...
Ready cheer three.
三號歡呼準備
- or should you...  - Roll.
- 還是...  - 開始
And the answer is, who cares about the Dow?
答案是 誰在乎道鐘斯指數?
It's a measly 30 companies.
只不過有30間公司
So why do you people keep paying attention to it?
那麼為什麼大家還這麼關心?
Probably because our network insists on tracking it.
也許是因為我們的網路 堅持要跟蹤它的資訊
- Right here at the bottom of the screen...  - Not sticking to the script.
- 就在這個螢幕下方...  - 不跟稿子念
in large font all day.
全天一排大字
- Why does he keep talking?  - And why do they do that?
- 他怎麼還在說?  - 為何如此?
Sacajawea, Lee.
薩卡加維亞 利
Because you people keep paying so much attention to it.
因為你們一直關注它
Sacajawea.
薩卡加維亞
- And the circle just keeps on turning.  - Shut up.
- 所以就一直播  - 閉嘴
Thank you.
謝謝
So let's try to ignore it. Let's try to ignore it for one day.
所以我們試試忽視它 試試忽視它一天
One day, and talk about the thing that everybody else is talking about.
就一天 我們來說說大家都在說的事
Ibis Clear Capital is down another quarter to $8.40,
埃比斯金融公司又下跌了0.25 跌至每股8.4美金
but rather than grabbing the third rail
但不要去摸電線自殺
and losing control of our bowels,
而令情況失控
we here at Money Monster like to go...
我們《金錢怪獸》要...
Straight to the Source!
直取問題的源頭
Straight to the source.
直取源頭
As it turns out, Walt Camby is 35,000 feet in the air right now,
華特·坎比此刻坐飛機在十千米高空
but we have somebody far prettier right here at sea level.
但我們在地面上找到了另一個人
It's his right-hand gal, Diane...
他的得力助手 黛安...
- It's Lester.  - Lester.
- 是萊斯特  - 萊斯特
Is gonna be on the show in a little while to explain
將做客本期節目
not only what went wrong last week,
不僅解釋上周發生的事件
but, more importantly, what they're gonna do to fix it.
更重要的是 她將告訴我們如何解決事件
But first, let's talk market Movers and Shakers.
但首先 我們來說說 市場上呼風喚雨的人
Jim, cue clip package two and three in case he skips one.
吉姆 請準備二號和三號片段 以防他跳過一號
Two and three?
二號和三號?
You're wondering, "Should I sell? Should I unload?"
你還在想 "我該賣出嗎? 該放棄嗎?"
(北部探索呼風喚雨)
You know what I'm gonna say to you.
你知道我要告訴你什麼
Roll balls.
放球
Grow some balls, man! Man up!
鼓起勇氣來 做個男子漢
Good one.
說得好
Man up! Lenny, let me hear you say it.
做個男子漢 蘭尼 我要聽你說一遍
Man up!
男子漢
Lenny, let me hear it.
蘭尼 說出來
Look at these numbers. See these?
看看這些數字 看見了?
These are the stock prices over the last three months.
這些是過去三個月的股票價格
See these drops?
看到這些下跌的了?
Get used to it. It's just the way the market works these days.
習慣了就好 如今的市場就是這樣
Look at this. $3.50 here. Almost five bucks there.
看看這裡 3.5美金 差不多5美金
If you panicked here, you would have sold...
你若驚恐 你就會賣出...
- Who's that guy?  - Who's what guy?
- 那傢伙是誰?  - 什麼傢伙?
- you whiners, you chickens.  - Camera 2.
- 你們這些牢騷大王 膽小鬼  - 2號機
You know what I'm gonna tell you to do.
你知道我會對你說什麼
Mark, can you pan over? Do you see that guy?
馬克 你能搖過去一點兒嗎? 看得見那個人嗎?
We're talking about 89% return. Even the Teamsters get excited about these numbers.
這可是89%回報呀 就連老師們都為此興奮
Somebody didn't tell me something.
某人對我隱瞞了某事
Looks like a delivery guy.
好像是個送貨的
Say it. I'm not gonna move until you say it.
快說 你不說我就不繼續
(漢子)
- Balls.  - Balls!
- 漢子  - 漢子
There it is! Just under the wire.
對啦 時間正好
All right. Now, for the rest of you, you know what that means.
好啦 你們其他人 知道這是什麼意思了
It's time for today's "Can't Miss Stock Tip of the Millennium."
又到了"千禧年股票市場提示"
It's the Stock Tip of the Millennium.
千禧年股票市場提示
Telecommunications. Forget the top-rated stocks.
電訊科技 別管那些排名靠前的股票了
Well, here he comes.
他來了
Okay, Mark, stay with this guy. I don't know who he is.
馬克 你盯住這個人 我不知道他是誰
Alan, there's no chance he's miked, so just boom him in.
亞蘭 他身上不可能有麥克風 你用話筒收他的聲音
Let's see what happens.
看看怎麼回事
Hopefully you've been listening to our little birdy.
希望你們都在聽這小鳥說的話
Where's that stupid parrot?
那個傻鸚鵡呢?
You got a delivery?
送貨嗎?
Don't move.
別動
Is this a union thing?
這是打彩帶的槍嗎?
Jesus!
天呀
Cut the feed.
停播
(財經有線電視 技術故障 請待命)
Turn those cameras back on!
別關攝像機
- Turn those cameras back on!  - Jesus Christ!
- 把攝像機都打開  - 我的天呀
Whoever's in there, turn those cameras back on, right now!
裡面的人 快把攝像機打開
- I can't. Once I turn them off...  - You're lying!
- 不行 一旦關閉...  - 你撒謊
Turn the cameras back on or I'm gonna shoot him in his head!
把攝像機打開 不然我朝他的頭開槍了
Turn the cameras on, Patty! Turn them on!
快開攝像機 帕蒂 快開
Patty?
帕蒂?
Patty!
喂
All right, I'm gonna count to three,
我數三下
- then I swear to God...  - Do something!
- 我對天發誓  - 做點什麼
- I'm pulling this trigger. One...  - Patty!
- 我會扣動扳機的  - 帕蒂
Patty, what do you want me to do?
帕蒂 怎麼辦?
- Turn them on, Patty!  - Two...
- 開攝像機 帕蒂  - 二...
- Patty!  - Three!
- 帕蒂  - 三
- What do you want me to do?  - Put it up.
- 怎麼辦?  - 開機
Are we live?
是直播嗎?
Yeah, we're live.
對 是直播
All right, turn the cameras off again
好 你們再敢關攝像機
I'm gonna shoot him in his head. You hear me?
我就斃了他 明白嗎?
Everybody understands.
所有人都明白
- Don't try any tricks with the monitors.  - Call security.
- 鏡頭都別耍花樣  - 叫保安
I got the whole broadcast here on my phone.
我手機上就能看直播
If I see anything other than us, I'm gonna shoot him in his head, all right?
要是看不到我們 我就斃了他 知道嗎?
- Do you understand me?  - Everybody understands you.
- 你們明白嗎?  - 大家都明白
Everybody understands. We stay on the air. All right.
大家都明白 我們在直播 沒事
- We're staying on the air.  - Good.
- 我們保持直播  - 好
Good.
很好
No, wait.
等等
He's not picking up.
保安不接電話
Pick a box.
選個箱子
What do you mean?
你什麼意思?
- I said, "Pick a box."  - What happens if I pick the wrong box?
- 我說"選個箱子"  - 我若選錯了會怎樣?
I said pick one!
快選一個
- I'm not picking a fucking box!  - Did he say "fucking" on air?
- 我他媽就不選  - 他直播說"他媽的"?
Are you fucking kidding? Call fucking security!
你他媽開什麼玩笑? 快他媽叫保安
Hi, there's a guy with a gun in studio 3.
3號攝影棚有人持槍
It sounds like a real cute stunt today.
好像今天的玩笑特別好玩
Would you turn on the goddamn TV? It's not a stunt this time.
你把電視打開看看行嗎? 這次不是惡作劇
- I need help. Help me, help me.  - Jesus!
- 救救我 救命 救命  - 天呐
Stupid son of a bitch.
狗娘養的
Pick a goddamn box, Lee. Come on!
選個箱子 利 快點兒
Come on, Lee.
快點兒 利
Do it!
選呀
That's right. Open it up.
這就對了 打開
Jesus Christ.
我的天呀
Now, pick it up.
拿出來
Yep. Take it out.
對 拿出來
- Now put it on.  - How do I know it won't blow up?
- 穿上  - 我怎麼知道這不會爆炸?
'Cause I have the detonator. All right?
因為引爆器在我這 好嗎?
If my thumb comes off this trigger, then we all explode.
我的大拇指一抬起來 大家就都炸了
- What if your thumb gets tired?  - You better hope it doesn't.
- 你的手指頭累了怎麼辦?  - 最好希望它別累
Now put it on.
穿上
Quickly!
快點兒
- Okay, listen up, everybody.  - Put it on.
- 好 大家聽好  - 穿上
If you're not manning a camera or a boom, get out right now.
除了控制攝像機和話筒的人 其他人馬上離開
Stop what you're doing.
放下手上的工作
If you're not core-one control room, get going.
中心控制室以外的人 都離開
Don't look up. Just go.
別四顧 快走
Right now.
現在就走
Button it up.
系上扣子
Good.
好
Sit down.
坐下
Something's wrong.
不太對勁
- Oh, my God.  - Breathe, Lee.
- 天呐  - 深呼吸 利
I can't catch my breath.
我喘不上來氣
Just stay calm. Don't panic. You can breathe.
保持冷靜 別慌 你能呼吸
I'm having a heart attack.
心臟病要犯了
- Do I look stupid to you?  - You are not having a heart attack.
- 我這樣子是不是特傻?  - 你沒犯心臟病
- Just breathe.  - I can't breathe.
- 深呼吸  - 我呼吸不了
- Just breathe.  - Oh, God.
- 呼吸  - 天呐
Patty, I'm gonna fucking die.
帕蒂 我他媽要死了
- No, you're not.  - You're not gonna die, dipshit. Not yet.
- 不會的  - 你還不會死 混蛋
- Fuck you! I'm having a fucking heart attack.  - You're not having a heart attack.
- 操 我他媽犯心臟病了  - 你沒犯心臟病
- You're having a panic attack.  - How do you know?
- 你這是恐慌症  - 你怎麼知道?
'Cause it happens to me all the time. Here, drink some water.
因為我總犯 給你 喝口水
That's not water.
這個不是水
Lee, I want you to hear my voice. I'm right here.
利 我要你聽我說 我就在這
Just keep breathing.
保持呼吸
Shots have been fired at FNN
財經有線電視發生槍擊
- on the set of Money Monster with Lee Gates.  - Bring it here.
- 利·蓋茲的《金錢怪獸》的直播現場  - 拿過來
An intruder found his way into the studio...
入侵者進入攝影棚...
Turn on FNN, Money Monster. Lee Gates has been taken hostage.
快看財經有線電視的《金錢怪獸》 利·蓋茲被綁架了
Shit.
該死
- Shut those doors!  - Okay. Okay.
- 關門  - 好
I see you.
我看見你了
Hey! Get out of there! Nobody goes in the booth, all right?
喂 快離開 別靠近舞臺好嗎?
Nobody's leaving from here on out.
任何人都不准離開這裡
Anybody tries anything stupid,
要是有人耍花招
and I start shooting.
我就開槍
All right? I'm in charge.
聽見了嗎? 我說了算
You! Stay still. Stop fucking moving.
你 別動 你他媽別動
I got something I wanna say.
我有話想說
- Patty, what do you want me to do?  - Wanna make sure I get time to say it.
- 帕蒂 我怎麼辦?  - 我有話要說
Follow him.
拍他
All right.
好
I want everyone to know something.
我想讓大家都知道件事
I might be the one with the gun here,
也許拿著槍的是我
but I'm not the real criminal. It's people like these guys!
但我不是真正的罪犯 罪犯是像他們這樣的人
They're stealing everything from us and they're getting away with it, too.
他們從我們口袋裡把錢偷走 還不會獲罪
Nobody's asking how. Nobody's asking why.
沒人問怎麼回事或為什麼
I didn't steal anything from you.
我沒偷你的錢
Be quiet, Lee.
別說話 利
You got to open your eyes out there.
你們要睜開眼好好看看
It's not like the government's no help.
政府並非沒有用
How they just look the other way, since after they're done stealing our money,
他們只是用另一種方式看問題 自從他們偷完我們的錢
they barely even have to pay any taxes on it!
他們幾乎不用上稅
I'm telling you, it's rigged. The whole goddamn thing.
我告訴你們 有人操縱 整件事都是被操縱的
They're stealing the country out from under us.
他們從我們眼皮底下 偷走了整個國家
Not the Muslims. Not the Chinese. Them.
不是穆斯林 不是中國人 是他們
- Let me ask you this...  - Shut up, Lee! Shut the fuck up!
- 我問你...  - 閉嘴 利 你他媽閉嘴
Shut up!
閉嘴
I came here to talk! Shut up for two minutes.
我是來說話的 你把嘴閉上
All right. Okay.
好
Jesus Christ.
天呐
It's all fixed.
都是定好了的
They like how the math adds up, so they got to keep rewriting the equation.
他們喜歡數字一路加上去 所以他們就改寫了等式
Which means, the one time you finally get a little extra money,
也就是說 一旦你終於賺了點兒小錢
you try and be smart about it, you turn on the TV.
你努力想明智些 你打開電視
That's how they fucking take it.
他們就他媽拿走啦
They take it so fast they don't even have to explain it!
他們手很快 甚至不需要解釋
They literally own the airwaves.
他們真正擁有電波
They literally control the information. But not today.
他們真正控制資訊 但今天不是
- What does this have to do with me?  - Everything, Lee.
- 這跟我有什麼關係?  - 一切都有關係 利
This has everything to do with the both of you.
一切跟你們倆都有關係
That's why I'm here. Don't you understand?
所以我才來的 你明白嗎?
Two boxes.
兩個箱子
Two assholes.
給兩個混蛋
Two?
兩個?
Two.
兩個
You didn't just come here for me.
你不僅是來找我的
This is about Ibis.
是埃比斯
- Goddamn right, this is about Ibis.  - Okay, I get it.
- 沒錯 就是埃比斯  - 好 我懂了
Turn that camera off.
把攝像機關了
Turn the camera off.
You lost a lot of money.
你損失了好多錢
You went on TV. You said it was safe.
你在電視上說那很安全
Four weeks ago. You stood right there.
就在四周前 就在這裡
This is what you did. "Let's get into this."
這就是你說的 "我們投錢吧"
- "Ibis! Safer than a savings account!"  - I didn't say that.
- "埃比斯 比儲蓄帳戶還安全"  - 我沒說過
"Home run after home run... Walt Camby!"
"一個本壘打接一個本壘打 華特·坎比"
- I didn't do that!  - Don't fucking lie, Lee! That's what you said.
- 我沒說過  - 別他媽撒謊 你就是這麼說的
I did recommend it, but I never said it was safer than a savings account.
我的確推薦過這支股票 但我從沒說過比存錢還安全
You want to bet? Come on, let's bet.
你想打賭嗎? 打個賭
You said it was safer than my savings account.
你說過比存錢還重要
- I would never say it.  - Come on. Let's bet.
- 我永遠不會這麼說  - 來吧 打個賭
March the 6th, it was Stock Pick of the Millennium. March the 6th.
3月6號的 "千禧年股票市場提示"
I make a stock pick every single day. That's a fucking joke.
我每天都播出股票提示 只是開個玩笑而已
You got the tapes back there, right?
你們有錄影吧?
Fuck off.
去你的吧
Find it.
找出來
- March the 6th show.  - We do five shows a week.
- 3月6號的節目  - 我們每週做五次節目
Find them!
找出來
How many people are inside?
裡面有多少人?
A floor manager, a sound engineer,
一個現場經理 一個音效師
and three cameramen on the main floor.
舞臺上三個攝像師
And the director, Patty Fenn.
還有導演帕蒂·芬恩
And five tech guys in the enclosed control room.
還有五個技術人員 在封閉控制室裡
Okay, ESU will be here momentarily.
緊急事件小組馬上就到
So, we're gonna need schematics on the building.
我們需要大樓的圖紙
Catwalks, exits, entrances, the whole shebang.
走廊 出口 入口等所有東西
Got it.
明白
Vasquez?
瓦斯凱?
If that's Semtex, it's enough for a fireball 50-feet from center.
森泰克斯炸藥  一旦爆炸將造成半徑15米火球
I got a line to the control room yet?
跟控制室通上話了嗎?
Evacuate the rest of the building. Once it's swept, nobody in or out.
疏散大樓內所有人員 然後不准再有人出入
Come on. Let's go.
快 播出來
Shuttle, shuttle, shuttle.
快進 快進
Diversify, diversify, diversify.
多元投資 多元投資
Freeze. There it is. Okay, we've got it.
停 就這 好了
- Roll it, Jim.  - Rolling.
- 放出來 吉姆  - 放出來
There it is! That's it. Let's settle this right now.
就是這個 就是 現在就一見分曉吧
The name is Lee Gates. The show is Money Monster.
我是利·蓋茲 這裡是《金錢怪獸》
The day is Friday, March 6th. Let's get right to it.
今天是星期五 3月6日 節目現在開始
It's the Stock Tip of the Millennium!
千禧年股票市場提示
Let's see what old lucky one-arm has for us today.
讓我們來看看 今天的幸運股票是哪一支
Ibis Clear Capital.
埃比斯金融公司
I know, I've talked this one up before, but what can I tell you?
我知道 我以前說過這個 但我能告訴你什麼呢?
I'm in love.
我愛上它了
This is Ibis's stock since it went public 11 months ago.
這是埃比斯股票 發行11月以來的走勢
Look at those curves. So voluptuous.
看看這個弧度 多麼妖燒
So full-figured!
多麼明白
I'm genuinely attracted to it.
我真的愛上它了
Not sexually so much,
不是那麼性感
although after half a dozen vodka tonics I could talk myself into pretty much anything.
喝了半打伏特加滋補身子後 我幾乎什麼都信
No. I am in love with this intellectually.
不 我是真的理性地愛上了這支股票
Because Ibis is run by a man named Walt Camby.
因為埃比斯的老闆 是個叫華特·坎比的人
Walt was one of the first guys to tap into the true market potential
華特是最早真正利用股市的
of high-frequency trading.
高頻率交易潛力的人之一
Look at this. Home run after home run after home run.
看看這個 一個本壘打接一個本壘打
And now he has finally gone public.
如今他終於上市了
Folks, there isn't a better bet out there. Not bonds, not IRAs,
各位 沒有比這更好的投資產品了 不是債券 不是退休存款
not your savings account.
不是儲蓄戶口
None of them are as safe as Walt Camby.
這些都不如華特·坎比安全
Cut it, Jim.
切掉 吉姆
Patty, put the numbers back up there. Give me another fix.
帕蒂 把盈利放上來 我要更多確鑿證據
Come on. Oh, my God, I'm going weak in the knees.
拜託 我都站不住了
- I was exaggerating to make a point.  - You lost a bet, Lee.
- 我說話比較誇張  - 你賭輸了 利
I made a bad call. How much are you into Ibis for?
我的預期錯誤 你買了埃比斯多少?
Sixty grand.
六萬美金
Sixty grand? This is about sixty grand?
六萬美金? 是六萬美金?
Pocket change to you, right?
對你來說不算什麼是吧?
Yeah, it kind of is. Okay, look.
的確是 聽著
You give me five minutes, and I can get you 60 grand in cash here,
你給我五分鐘 我能給你六萬現金
and I can make you whole.
就還清了
- That won't make me whole.  - All right. What's a number that will?
- 還不清  - 好吧 那你要多少?
$800 million.
八億美金
It's gonna take me a little longer to get $800 million here, pal.
弄八億美金可能會花些時間
That's how much went fucking poof into thin air, you dumb shit.
他們蒸發的錢就是這麼多 你這個蠢蛋
So that's what you owe us. 'Cause I'm not the only one watching your show.
所以你就欠這麼多 我不是唯一看你節目的人
I'm not the only shareholder who got screwed over here.
我不是唯一被套牢的投資者
You're the only shareholder here with a gun.
但你是唯一持槍的投資者
You think you're fucking funny, Lee? Is this funny to you?
你覺得自己他媽很好笑 利? 你覺得好笑嗎?
Lee, don't provoke him.
利 別激他
You must think I'm so stupid.
你一定覺得我很傻吧
Trying to fucking buy me off.
你他媽想拿錢了事
I'm not stupid, Lee.
我不傻 利
I walked in here knowing there was only one way this show was gonna end.
我走進來時 就知道這個節目只有一種結束方式
I came in here knowing I'm not walking out.
我進來時就知道我不會走出去
Sit down.
坐下
Where the hell is ESU? And where's my negotiator?
緊急事件小組呢? 談判專家呢?
Negotiator's two minutes out.
談判專家兩分鐘到位
- Patty Fenn.  - This is Captain Marcus Powell.
- 帕蒂·芬恩  - 我是馬克斯·鮑威爾警監
The network confirmed you can stay live on the air.
電視公司確認 你們可以繼續直播
Just keep stalling him.
請繼續拖住他
What do you mean "keep stalling"?
"拖住"什麼意思?
Tell him to say whatever it is this guy wants to hear until we put a plan in place,
讓他說這傢伙想聽的 直到我們準備就緒
whatever it takes to keep him from setting off that bomb.
無論如何要防止他引爆炸彈
Jesus.
天呐
Fuck off.
操
Lee? You have to keep stalling.
利? 你要拖住他
Just keep talking to him.
繼續跟他說話
You're good at that. So just keep talking.
這你可最拿手 不停說話
Talk.
說話
Listen, I get it. What happened at Ibis is... It's a disaster, there's no other word for it.
聽著 我明白 埃比斯的事是個災難 沒有別的形容
I can promise you that Walt Camby
我可以想你保證 華特·坎比
is as sick about this as anybody else.
跟所有人一樣難受
Yeah? Is that what he told you from his private fucking jet?
是嗎? 他在私人飛機上 就是這麼跟你說的?
Listen, if anybody is gonna bounce back from it,
聽著 股票會回升的
it's Walt and Ibis. This was an isolated incident.
是華特和埃比斯 那是孤立意外事件
What's this?
這是什麼?
What is this? Who wrote this?
這是什麼? 誰寫的?
- Somebody from my office.  - "Diane Lester."
- 我的同事  - "黛安·萊斯特"
You see? This is what I'm talking about. That's your problem.
你看? 就是這個 這就是你的問題
You just sit there behind their little fucking desk,
他們就坐在他們的破桌子後面
like their little fucking puppet, buying into their bullshit,
就像他們的小玩偶 他們什麼廢話都信
instead of trying to figure out what really happened.
卻不去看看實際怎麼回事
You know what happened. It was a computer glitch.
你知道怎麼回事 是電腦故障
A glitch! A glitch! It was a fucking glitch! A glitch!
故障 故障 是他媽的故障 故障
Shut up about the glitch!
別再說故障了
All right?
行嗎?
What the hell does that even mean?
這詞究竟什麼意思?
You see, you don't even know. I'm not stupid, Lee. I told you.
你看你都不知道 我不傻 利 我說了
People just at home accepting this shit, they're the stupid ones,
坐在家裡接受這廢話的人 他們才傻呢
because somehow these clowns
因為不知怎的這些小丑們
lost $800 million overnight.
一夜之間損失了八個億
Overnight.
一夜之間
And nobody's even actually explained how.
甚至沒人能解釋怎麼回事
How is something like that even possible?
怎麼竟然會發生這種事呢?
How is that even fair?
這公平嗎?
How's that fair?
公平嗎?
It's not a rhetorical question. I want a fucking answer.
不是反問 他媽的回答我
What do you want from me, man?
你想我怎樣 夥計?
I don't run Ibis. I'm just a guy on TV.
埃比斯又不是我管 我只是個做電視節目的
No, no. Do not do that, Lee. Do not do that.
不 別這麼說 利 別這麼說
You don't get to pass the buck today, Lee.
你今天不能逃避責任 利
Not today. Not with me.
今天不行 跟我不行
So, what do we know about him so far?
目前我們對他有何瞭解?
Name's Kyle Budwell. No wants, no warrants, no priors.
他叫科爾·巴德維爾 沒有被通緝過 搜查或警告過
We sent a patrol to his residence to locate family.
我們派了一個巡警 去他家確認其家人
They won't find anyone. The guy's a loner.
他家什麼人都沒有 是個單身漢
Hundred bucks says this poor shithead either lives by himself or with his mother.
我賭一百塊錢 這個可憐蟲不是自己住就是跟他媽住
The real losers tend to stay home with their mommies.
一般社會渣滓都是跟媽媽過
But, hey, do your thing. But watch and see, the guy's a loner.
但是 你幹活去吧 小心看著 這個傢伙是個單身漢
Yes?
喂
Can you patch this line directly into the studio PA system for us, please, Patty?
帕蒂 你能將這個電話直接轉入 攝影棚的廣播系統嗎?
- We have a negotiator here.  - Okay.
- 談判專家來了  - 好
Charlie? Patch this line into the PA system, please. Right now.
查理? 將電話接入廣播系統 趕快
It's all about... It's high-frequency trading. It can...
一切都是高頻率交易的事
Let us know when we're on.
接好了告訴我們
Can he hear me?
他聽得到嗎?
This is Oscar Nelson. I'm a veteran negotiator with the NYPD.
我是奧斯卡·尼爾森 紐約警察局的談判專家
No. I don't want to talk to no cops.
我不想跟員警說話
Don't think of me as a cop.
別把我當員警
Hey, what'd I just say? No cops!
沒聽見我說的嗎? 別叫員警
Cut the line! Cut it.
切斷 切掉
I can handle it myself.
我自己能應付
Anybody comes on that mike,
再有人用麥克風說話
you gonna put a bullet in his head. You hear me?
我就斃了他 明白了嗎?
- Cut the line. Cut it.  - Cut the line, Charlie. Right now.
- 掛電話  - 掛電話 查理 馬上
Do not cut this...
別掛...
Two people I came here to talk to. Him and Walt fucking Camby.
我來這裡是要找兩個人 他和該死的華特·坎比
All right, well, then let's get him Walt fucking Camby already.
那就給他該死的華特·坎比
All right, so let's get him Walt fucking Camby already.
好吧 那就給他該死的華特·坎比
Right. Exactly. Throw him under the bus.
沒錯 就這樣 讓他做替罪羊
Look, he was supposed to be here today. He didn't show up.
他今天該來的 他沒來
It's his company. It's his crash. So let's see what he has to say.
那是他的公司 他的錢 所以看看他有什麼話說
Right. Yes.
好 可以
- What happened to the Ibis feed?  - I have no idea.
- 埃比斯的鏡頭怎麼了?  - 我不知道
God damn it.
該死的
All right, find me Bree.
找布瑞
Have her call Diane Lester back on the phone.
讓她叫黛安·萊斯特回來
I want her back up on that screen.
我想讓她回到大螢幕
And find out everything and anything you can about Ibis Clear Capital.
盡可能找到一切關於埃比斯金融公司的東西
- Got it.  - Yes, what is it?
- 明白  - 喂 什麼事?
I want the PA system available in case we need to speak to him again.
準備廣播系統 以防萬一我們需要和他對話
Right. Because it worked so well the first time.
好 因為第一次"很有效"
Look, just make sure you answer this phone.
聽著 你一定要接電話
We'll be right downstairs exploring means of extraction.
我們就在樓下 正在討論營救方案
I have Patty Fenn from Money Monster on line three.
《金錢怪獸》的帕蒂·芬恩在三線
Marta, when is he landing?
瑪塔 飛機幾點降落?
I don't even know which plane he's on, so I've no way of tracking him.
我不知道他的行程 所以我沒法追蹤他
He took the G-V to Geneva on Tuesday,
他週二乘GV去了日內瓦
but then he sent that to Hong Kong to pick up Harvey Bergan.
但後來他又去香港接哈威伯根
Last location I have for the Learjet was Sao Paulo on Monday.
我能查到他飛機的最後一站是 週一在聖保羅
Monday? That's four days ago.
週一? 那都四天了
You know how he is with his planes. When he's in the air, he's off the grid.
你知道他怎麼用飛機的 他在天上的時候斷絕聯繫
Are you telling me that until he lands, whenever the hell that may be, that he's...
你是說不到他降落 不管什麼時候 他...
He's completely unreachable. Which makes this one big clusterfuck.
就根本找不到他 也就導致這次大災難
I have Patty Fenn on hold. What should I tell her?
帕蒂·芬恩還在等呢 怎麼跟她說?
She'll call back.
她會再打的
Come on.
拜託
Diane Lester's office is giving me the runaround.
黛安·萊斯特的辦公室 給了我行程表
Okay, Bree.
好 布瑞
Dave, I need an address for Ibis, ASAP.
戴夫 儘快給我埃比斯的地址
And, Bree, try Dan Issa at the SEC.
布瑞 試試給美國證交會的丹·伊薩打電話
They've got to be sniffing around this train wreck already.
他們肯定已經開始調查這個爛攤子了
Keep stalling, Lee. We're on it.
繼續拖住他 利 我們在努力了
Lenny, can you come around on this guy? I'm losing him in a little shadow.
蘭尼 你能追住這個傢伙嗎? 他在陰影裡我看不太清楚
- You kidding me?  - Just move in.
- 開玩笑呀你?  - 你就拍吧
What the hell are you doing?
你在幹嘛?
Director wanted a better angle on your face.
導演說要好好看看你的臉
There's kind of a...
有點兒...
A little shadow.
陰影
"A little shadow"?
"有點兒陰影"?
Patty, "A little shadow"?
帕蒂 "有點兒陰影"?
He could have killed you much easier off camera, Lee.
他在鏡頭外會很輕易殺了你 利
There's a reason he's interrupted you on live TV.
他在直播現場找你是有原因的
Look, give me a break, guy. I'm just trying to do my job.
饒了我吧 夥計 我只是在做我該做的
They tell me to move in, I move in.
他們告訴我進來 我就進來
All right, where do you want to go?
好吧 你想去哪?
Well, if you went over there, it would be good.
你要是去那邊會很好
- Here?  - Yeah.
- 這?  - 對
See, I'm directing a show back here, which means you're hosting one up there.
你看 我正在導演一場節目 也就是說你在主持這個節目
So start hosting.
所以 開始主持吧
Okay, first things first.
好吧 先做緊要的
- What's your name?  - Don't worry about my name.
- 你叫什麼名字?  - 別管我叫什麼
You're on TV. Trust me.
你上電視呢 信我
They're gonna know your Little League batting average by the time this is through.
他們這會兒工夫早就知道你的底細了
His name is Kyle Budwell. The cops already tracked down his info.
他叫科爾·巴德維爾 員警已經查到他的資訊了
Doesn't even have to be your real name. Just give me anything I can call you.
不用告訴我真名 我只是想稱呼你
Fine. Call me Kyle.
好吧 叫我科爾
Okay, Kyle.
好的 科爾
Got the address.
有地址了
All right, that's midtown. Listen, Ibis is ducking our calls.
好 在市中心 埃比斯不接我們電話
I say we send somebody there in person instead.
我想派個人親自去
- All right.  - Alan, see if you can put a mike on this guy.
- 好吧  - 亞蘭 看能不能給這傢伙一個麥克風
Lee, talk him through this. I don't want him spooked.
利 你跟他說說這事 我不想嚇著他
- Kyle, listen.  - Yeah.
- 科爾 聽著  - 好
This is Alan. He's our sound guy.
這是亞蘭 他是管音效的
He wants to put a microphone on you, so you can... No, it's okay. It's okay.
他想給你帶個麥克風 你就能... 沒關係的
You want people to be able to hear you, right?
你想讓大家都聽見吧?
- Why, they couldn't hear me before?  - They could... This will be better.
- 為什麼 他們之前聽不到嗎?  - 能聽到 但是有話筒好些
We're tracking down Ron now. I'm gonna put him on the air with you.
我們正在聯繫羅恩 我會播出他和你的對話
- Kyle.  - Yeah?
- 科爾  - 什麼?
I'm gonna send one of my guys over to Ibis's office
我會派人去埃比斯的辦公室
and see if they can get some answers in person.
看看他們能否親自得到些答覆
We've got a producer. This kid's name is Ron.
我們有個製片人叫羅恩
Where the hell is Ron Sprecher?
羅恩·斯普雷徹到底在哪?
- Christ!  - Oh, my God!
- 天  - 天呀
Ron! This stuff really works!
羅恩 這東西還真有用
- What's the stock trading at?  - $4.25.
- 這家公司現在行情如何?  - 每股4.25美金
Christ!
天
Shit, shit, shit. Shit. My phone.
該死 我的電話
- No, it's okay. I need a break, anyway.  - Hold on.
- 沒事 反正我需要休息  - 等等
- Yeah?  - Hang on, Ron.
- 喂?  - 等等 羅恩
Hey, Charlie.
喂 查理
Hi, Ron. I'm gonna put you on the air with Lee.
羅恩你好 我會播出你和利的對話
Lee, you've got Ron. Patching Ron in.
利 羅恩接通了 切入羅恩
What do you mean you're putting me on the air?
你說播出是什麼意思?
You're going on the air?
你要直播了?
Who is that? Where are you?
那是誰? 你在哪?
I'm in my office with Arlene.
我跟愛琳在辦公室
Who'd you just tell my name to?
你跟誰說我的名字呢?
Is that Arlene from Product Placement?
商品廣告部的愛琳?
Get off my jeans.
別踩著我的褲子
I thought you said the building was cleared.
你不是說大樓都清空了嗎
It was. We walked every floor.
的確 我們每層都查過
So, what's up, Lee?
怎麼回事 利?
Hey, are you coming back?
你還回來嗎?
Where are you right now?
你現在哪裡?
I've just been going through tapes for tomorrow,
我只是在為明天翻看些錄影
but everything looks good, so I think we should be in good shape, so...
但一切正常 我想我們會順利的
Holy shit! That guy has a gun!
靠 那人拿著槍
Imagine my surprise.
想想我有多驚訝
Now, do us a favor and get your ass down to Ibis Clear Capital,
你幫我個忙 去趟埃比斯金融公司
would you, please?
可以嗎?
Okay.
好
I like when he has the strippers on.
我喜歡他的脫衣舞部分
Right. Right. Sure.
好 可以
- Don't be a schmuck, Ron. Get moving.  - Is this for real?
- 別這麼笨 羅恩 快去  - 是真的嗎?
Hey, turn it up, will you?
開大點兒聲行嗎?
There's a van and a crew waiting downstairs for you.
樓下有一輛車和一幫人等著你
Let's go. Come on. Move. You should be downstairs already. Let's go!
快去 快 你早該下樓了 快去
(首爾)
(雷克雅維克)
(約翰尼斯堡)
(南非新聞網)
What's taking them so long?
怎麼這麼慢?
It's midday traffic. What are you gonna do?
正午交通高峰 你說怎麼辦?
Got it.
明白
So the home address is outdated.
他家住址沒更新
The family that's in there now bought it six months ago
現在住在那裡的人家 是六個月前才買下的
from the estate of one Clara Budwell, a 62-years-old deceased woman.
以前是巴德維爾的房產 她62歲時過世的
Mama's boy. What'd I tell you?
跟媽媽住 我說的吧?
We tracked down the escrow company.
我們查到履約保證公司
They confirmed all the money from the sale went to her son. Guess how much?
他們確認了所有房款都給了她兒子 猜猜有多少?
Sixty grand.
六萬美金
It's a good thing you didn't bet me, pal, since he fits the profile to a fucking T.
幸好你沒跟我下賭 他真是被我說中了
There has to be a current address with the escrow company.
履約保證公司 那一定有他現在的住址
Somewhere they sent the check to.
他們寄錢的地方
- There is, but we need a subpoena to get it.  - Captain.
是有 但我們需要傳票才能查
Get somebody down to the courthouse, ASAP.
派人馬上去法庭
Judge Reiner. He'll expedite.
萊納法官會加快辦理
All right.
好的
We can try to gain access through catwalks here
我們能從這邊的走廊進去
(舞臺 控制室)
or a crawlspace here, and get them out through the hatch in the control room here.
或者這邊的夾縫 把他們從控制室轉移出來
First, we save the hostages. Second, we take out the psycho.
首先 我們要解救人質 然後 我們要降伏那個瘋子
Okay, we're here. Just give us a minute to get set up.
好 我們到了 給我一分鐘時間準備
- We've got Ron. I'm putting him up.  - Okay, here we go.
- 接通羅恩了 我要播出  - 好 可以了
We've got Ron Sprecher reporting from outside...
接通羅恩·斯普雷徹了 他從外面進行報導
As if this month couldn't get any worse.
這個月一件事比一件事糟
Ron, Ron, can you hear us?
羅恩 你能聽到我們嗎?
I'm here outside Ibis Clear Capital, where their CEO...
我現在埃比斯金融公司外 首席執行長官...
Security, there's a man down there with a camera crew.
保安 有個人帶著攝製組在外面
Make sure he doesn't get in the building under any circumstances.
確保他無論如何不會進來
What did Teterboro say, Marta?
泰特波羅怎麼說的 瑪塔?
I gave them the tail numbers of both of these planes,
我把兩架飛機的航線編號都給他們了
no communication with either.
但都沒有回復
Okay, I'm gonna down there and try and buy us some time.
好吧 我下樓去 儘量拖延一段時間
I mean, obviously, this guy just wants some answers.
我是說 顯然這個傢伙只是想要個答覆
So do we.
我們也想要答覆
If we knew how we lost $800 million, we wouldn't have lost $800 million.
若我們知道是怎麼賠了八億 我們當初就不會賠了
I get that, Avery, but we still have to say something.
我知道 艾弗裡 但我們仍舊總得說些什麼呀
Come on. You know Walt. He's an open book. I know if he was here...
拜託 你知道華特的 他開誠佈公 他若在這...
But he's not here, Diane. He's not here.
但他不在 黛安 他不在這裡
Okay, we can't just lock ourselves away here and do nothing and hope it disappears.
好吧 我們不能把自己封閉起來 什麼都不做就想事情化解
We are a publicly-traded company.
我們是上市公司
We've got shareholders. We've got a board of directors
我們有投資人 董事會
and we've got a CEO, even though we don't know where he is right now.
還有個行政長官 雖然不知道他現在哪裡
So, look, I'm happy to have this conversation again
聽著 我願意對話
when Walt lands, but until then, it's not our call to make.
但要等華特降落 在那之前不是我們的責任
So, he's got the stage all locked up. These are the exits, front and rear.
他把整個舞臺都鎖起來了 有出口 正面和背面
Now, the problem is,
現在問題是
this guy's got complete range of vision throughout the entire studio.
這個傢伙能看到整個舞臺
So our only chance for a clean shot
我們準確射擊的唯一機會
is from these catwalks above the stage.
是從舞臺上的走廊
We're putting a man in position there as we speak.
我們一邊說話 一邊在那裡安排人手了
What about the bomb?
炸彈呢?
This is definitely a dead man's switch here in his hand,
他手裡掌握著生死
which means, if you take him out without disarming the bomb first...
也就是說 若不能先讓他接觸引爆...
Got the warrant, got an address. Sending a patrol there now.
我們有搜查令和地址了 現在正派人過去
Great.
很好
You see this bulge right here? That's the wireless receiver.
看到這個突起物了嗎? 這就是接受器
Now, Captain, if we can destroy that,
若我們能破壞這個
then the dead man's switch is just another fucking switch.
他手裡的人命開關就失靈了
Except, in order to destroy it, we got to what, shoot Gates?
為了破壞開關 我們要對蓋茲開槍嗎?
That's where this guy slipped up.
這是他不小心的地方
If he wanted to ensure a kill shot,
如果他想致其死地
he should've put the receiver here, right over the poor bastard's heart.
他就應該把接收器放在這 這個倒楣蛋的心臟前面
But instead, he put it down here next to his left kidney.
但他沒有 他放在靠近左腎這裡
If the bullet's on target, we get to him quick enough to avoid too much blood loss,
若子彈射中了 我們就快速營救避免失血過多
there's a good chance, Captain, he could survive it.
這是個好機會 警監
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Are you proposing we shoot the star of a TV show
你建議我們朝電視明星射擊
live, on air, in front of millions of people?
當著數百萬人的面現場直播?
Yeah.
對
I need you to talk to somebody from Ibis Clear Capital.
我要你跟埃比斯金融公司的某人說話
I need to talk... You wanna touch me?
我需要對話... 你想碰我?
- Don't put your hands on me.  - Andre? It's okay.
- 你別碰我  - 安德列? 可以了
- That's, that's...  - Diane Lester. I'll be happy to talk to you.
- 那是...  - 黛安·萊斯特 我願意跟你對話
Do you have an earpiece so I can hear everyone?
有耳機嗎? 我想聽大家說話
- Yes. Yeah.  - Okay, good.
- 有  - 好的
- Come on.  - All right.
- 拜託  - 好的
We're gonna talk to Diane Lester. She's the PR lady. She's the...
我們要跟黛安·萊斯特說話 她是做公關的 她是...
CCO.
首席通訊長官
Chief Communications Officer at Ibis. Diane?
埃比斯的首席通訊長官黛安?
Okay, get ready to put her on screen two. We're gonna put her on screen two.
好的 準備讓她出現在二號螢幕 我們用二號螢幕播出她的畫面
We're ready when you are.
你準備好了就開始
And go, Jim.
開始 吉姆
- Here she comes.  - All right.
她來了
First, let me start off by saying
首先 我想說的是
on behalf of everyone here at Ibis,
我代表埃比斯所有人
we are prepared to do whatever we can to get you to put down that gun, Mr. Budwell.
我們願意盡我們所能 讓你放下那把槍 巴德維爾先生
Now, I understand that you've offered to compensate him
我知道你已經提出
for his losses personally, Lee.
願意個人出資賠償他 利
Well, we are absolutely willing to do the same if it helps put an end to all this.
我們絕對也願意如此做 只要能幫助結束這一切
All right, you walk away now, double your money.
好了嗎 你現在走就可以拿雙份錢了
She knows my last name.
她知道我的姓
Everybody in the five boroughs knows your last name by now, Kyle.
所有五大行政區的人 都知道你姓什麼了 科爾
No, it's too late for your money, lady.
不 你現在給錢太遲了
All I want from you is an answer. I just wanna know what really happened?
我只是想要個說法 我只想知道到底發生了什麼?
Goddamn it!
該死的
Well, the truth is
事實是
we don't know.
我們不知道
We don't know why the algo suddenly went haywire.
我們不知道為什麼演算法突然失控
And we don't know why the fail-safes built to prevent...
我們也不知道為什麼 為此設立的故障保險...
God, I really hope she has more to say than "We don't know."
天呀 我真希望她不只會說"不知道"
We just don't know.
我們真的不知道
Are you kidding? This is all she's got? Are you kidding me?
你開玩笑呀? 她沒別的話說了? 你開什麼玩笑?
Sacajawea.
薩卡加維亞
Fine.
好吧
Are you watching this? This is getting out of control.
你在看嗎? 都失控了
The amount of scrutiny we're gonna get after this idiot blows himself up
等這個白癡把他自己炸了之後
is going to be unbelievable.
我們會面臨難以想像的調查
You thought it was bad before? It's about to get 100 times more intense.
你以為以前很糟? 會比這難處理一百倍
Look, don't worry, okay? We can handle it. Gates is an idiot.
別擔心好嗎? 我們能處理 蓋茲是個白癡
(華特·坎比)
Just stay the course, okay? I'm working Mambo night and day.
保持現狀好嗎? 我夜以繼日地處理曼博呢
I would like to point out that this affected all of us.
我想指出的是 這次事件影響到我們所有人
All our board, our managers, including myself.
所有董事 經理 包括我自己
Our pensions were depleted overnight.
我們的養老金一夜之間就沒有了
- Diane.  - Our savings gutted just like yours.
- 黛安  - 我們的存款跟你的一樣沒了
Wait. Wait. I'm sorry.
等等 抱歉
Are you trying to make me feel sorry for you?
你是在博取同情嗎?
Is that really what's happening right now?
是不是這樣?
- No, I just...  - That's exactly what's happening.
- 不 我只是...  - 就是這樣
I understand you want specifics.
我明白你想要細節
Yeah. So why doesn't she give him some specifics?
為什麼她就是不給他細節呢?
We know this was a completely isolated incident.
我們知道這次是一個絕對孤立事件
It's what we call a black swan.
我們稱之為黑天鵝
It's impossible to predict, but it's impossible to replicate.
無法預期 也無法複製
"Black swan"?
"黑天鵝"?
That's her memo.
是她的備忘錄
She's reading from her memo.
她在念備忘錄
Diane. Diane. We both read your talking points.
黛安 黛安 我們都看過你的對話要點
He doesn't want some PR spin about what's gonna go right next year.
他不想要什麼公關斡旋 談明年會發生什麼
He wants an explanation for what went wrong last week.
他只想知道上周發生了什麼
Yeah.
對
Right, I understand. And we believe in complete transparency.
好 我明白 我們相信徹底公開化
That's why we disclosed...
因此我們才公開了...
Where are your quants, Diane? Where are your quants?
定量分析師們呢 黛安? 分析師們呢?
- That's good. Go with that. Get an answer.  - I'm sorry?
- 很好 就這樣 讓她回答  - 你說什麼?
- Yeah.  - The quants you used.
- 是啊  - 你用的那些定量分析師
The guy who actually designed the algorithm that crashed.
那個實際設計了這個失敗演算法的人
Where is he? Is he in that building right there behind you?
他在哪裡? 在你身後那個大樓嗎?
'Cause I think I'd like to ask him a few questions.
因為我想問他幾個問題
No, these are our administrative offices. Our quants aren't...
不在 這裡是我們的行政大樓
Okay, then where is he? Is he in Mumbai?
那他在哪? 在孟買?
Russia? Yeah, he's in Russia. They're all in Russia.
俄羅斯? 對 他在俄國 他們都在俄國
I'm not sure.
我不知道
But if you'd like to talk to someone, then I can make that happen.
但你若想找人對話 我可以幫你聯繫
No, I don't want to talk to some low-level schlub, God damn it.
我不想跟什麼低水準的廢物說話
I want an explanation from you!
我要你解釋
And if you can't give me one, then I want to talk to Walt Camby.
你若不能解釋 那就讓華特·坎比跟我說
No, I'm sorry,
不 抱歉
- but Walt is on a plane right now.  - God damn...
- 但華特正在飛機上  - 該死的...
Shit-fucking assholes.
這他媽混蛋
I'm getting so tired of this same old bullshit over and over again, Lee.
我受夠了這些不斷重複的廢話 利
- Wait.  - Don't tell me to wait!
- 等等  - 別叫我等
What happened?
發生了什麼?
He just shot out your monitor on the stage
他在臺上對著你的螢幕發脾氣
because you're giving him the same corporate bullshit!
因為你說的都是些公司廢話
I'm not.
不是的
You have to understand how delicate of a situation this is.
你要理解現在的情況有多敏感
I'm sitting 80-feet from a bomb! Don't talk to me about delicate situations!
我25米外就是個炸彈 別跟我說什麼敏感情況
You have got to wake up and do the math here,
你要清醒一下 現在趕快想辦法
because it is not adding up to me, either.
因為我也沒有辦法
Why is that so goddamn hard?
為什麼這麼難?
Sorry, what do you mean?
你是什麼意思?
I mean, you better ask some real questions
我是說 你最好問些實際問題
and get some real answers, and hurry the fuck up!
然後做實質性回答 而且要他媽快
I want what happened to make sense!
我就想要個說法
Do not talk to him like that. Do not tell him things.
別這樣跟他說話 別指揮他
- Right now!  - Don't do anything stupid.
- 快點兒  - 別耍花招
Let me get you some answers.
我來要答案
You need to bargain for more time. All right?
你要跟他爭取時間 好嗎?
- Trade something.  - Give me 10 more minutes.
- 做些交易什麼的  - 再給我10秒鐘時間
Bargain with him.
跟他討價還價
Kyle, look.
科爾 你聽著
You give me something, I give you something. Okay?
你給我些東西 我就給你些東西 好嗎?
That's how this works.
要這樣做
You do something for me, I do something for you.
你為我做事 我就為你做
Come on.
拜託
Give me a chance.
給我個機會
Let me figure this out.
讓我想個辦法
- Fine, you got 10 minutes.  - Okay. All right.
- 好 給你10分鐘  - 好 可以
(紐約警察局 緊急事件小組)
Now what?
現在怎麼辦?
(利: 十分鐘內找到那個該死的分析師)
I made myself extraordinarily clear that you were not to go on camera.
我說得很清楚 你不能去面對鏡頭
I am curious. Who actually did design that algo?
我也很好奇 到底是誰設計的演算法?
Why don't we call him together?
為什麼不一起給他打電話?
Now, you listen to me, Diane. You're a CCO.
你聽我說 黛安 你是首席通訊長官
And that is all you are and that is nothing.
僅此而已 一文不值
I've seen a dozen girls like you come and go.
我見過好多你這樣的姑娘
- Really? Girls like me?  - Yeah!
- 真的? 我這樣的?  - 對
I don't have to stand here and listen to this.
我沒必要站在這裡聽這個
- Well, you're fired, Diane!  - You can't fire me. I don't report to you.
- 你被解雇了 黛安  - 你不能解雇我 你不是我上司
It's not our job to bail out this psychopath! Do not walk away from me!
解救這個瘋子不是我們的責任 別就這麼走了
I don't report to you, Avery.
你不是我的上司 艾弗裡
Ryan, get me a list of every quant that's been on our payroll since we went public.
瑞恩 給我自從上市以來 所有我們雇用的定量分析師名單
Walt's G-V radioed Teterboro. Twenty minutes out.
華特的飛機在泰特波羅 20分鐘了
Have a car waiting downstairs for me. And get me that list.
派輛車在樓下等我 把名單給我
This is Eagle One in first position. Proceeding to two.
我是鷹眼一號 在一號位 正向二號位前進
Bree, I asked for Dan Issa from the SEC.
布瑞 我讓你打給證交所的丹·伊薩
I called twice and left word both times.
我打了兩次 都留言了
All right, get me Ron.
好吧 接羅恩
Ron, I need you to go down to the SEC's offices on Vesey Street.
羅恩 你去維西街的證交所辦事處
Find Dan Issa. Do not take no for an answer. You have nine minutes.
去找丹·伊薩 不允許他們拒絕 你有9分鐘
Nine minutes?
9分鐘?
- Vesey Street's over a mile away.  - Then you better start running now.
- 維西街離這裡一個半公里呀  - 那你就最好趕快跑
Hey, Dave, can you pull up a stock price graphic for Ibis for me, please?
戴夫 可以放一個埃比斯的股市行情圖嗎?
- Okay. I'll need a second.  - Okay, then put their logo up on the nine-by.
- 要等一會兒  - 好 那就先放他們的商標
Okay.
好
Lee? How many people do you think are tuned into us right now at this moment?
利? 你認為現在有多少人在看直播?
Millions probably? Tens of millions?
幾百萬吧? 幾千萬?
That's tens of millions of investors,
那就是幾千萬個投資者
all with their fingers on their E-trade accounts.
全都有電子交易帳戶
Kyle, you bought Ibis at what, $75 a share?
科爾 埃比斯每股多少錢 75美金嗎?
- Yeah. So?  - What if we can get it back there?
- 對 怎麼了?  - 若我們能讓它漲回來呢?
How many times I gotta tell you, it's too late for your money.
還要我說多少次 現在給我錢太晚了
You're not the only shareholder that got screwed over.
你又不是唯一一個倒楣的投資者
You came here because you had something that you wanted to say.
你來這裡 是因為你有話要說
You want people to finally listen to you, right?
你想讓大家都聽到你說吧?
Yeah.
對
Well, now they can.
現在他們就能聽到
- Logo's ready.  - Put it up on the big screen.
- 商標準備好了  - 放上大螢幕
All right, Lee. Go to work.
好了 利 幹活吧
Watch what we can do.
看我們能做到什麼
(埃比斯金融公司)
I want to talk to everybody out there.
我想跟電視機前所有人說
Every single person that's watching me right now.
你們每一個正看著我的人
And here's what I want you to do.
我想讓你們這麼做
I want you to go to your computer
我想你們打開電腦
and I want you to buy Ibis stock.
買埃比斯的股票
I'm gonna be upfront with you.
我跟你們實話說
I don't want you to do it because you're gonna make money.
我想讓你們這麼做 不是為了讓你們賺錢
I want you to do it
我想讓你們這麼做
because it'll save my life.
因為這樣能救我的命
This is ballsy.
真夠勇的
The old Money Monster bump.
《金錢怪獸》慣用伎倆
The old Money Monster bump on a massive scale.
《金錢怪獸》慣用伎倆 這次是大規模的
- Where's my stock price?  - Just got it up.
- 股價圖呢?  - 剛準備好
It's simple math. Value comes from demand.
這個計算很簡單 價值由需求決定
So if every single one of you buys a few shares,
若你們每人買幾個股份
then we can get the price of this sucker up in no time.
那麼我們就能馬上讓股價回升
And here's the crazy part.
瘋狂的是
If we do it and everybody invests just a little bit of money,
若我們每人投資一點
the price starts to go up.
股價就會開始攀升
And then the algorithms... They start to take notice, and they start to buy it.
然後演算法... 就會留意到 他們就開始買入
Give it to me on the big screen.
給我放到大螢幕上
If you can fool them, then the sky's the limit!
無限增長
Which means that together we can turn a bad investment into a good one
也就是說 我們可以一起逆轉失敗投資
by sheer force of will.
全憑意志
Nice.
說得好
So, as of right now,
所以 現在
I am moving Ibis from a sell to a buy.
我要將埃比斯從賣出變成買進
He's gonna call a triple. Ready triple. Roll it.
他馬上會要"三倍" "三倍"準備 放
and make it a rare...
變成罕見的...
(買 買 買 三倍買入)
Triple Buy!
三倍買入
Come on. Come on.
拜託 拜託
Come on, you son of a bitch.
拜託 混蛋
Come on, guys.
拜託各位
We're human beings, we're not computers.
我們是人 不是電腦
We have a conscience.
我們有良心
Refresh, refresh.
更新 更新
- There it is.  - Yeah.
成功了
$8.48.
$8.48
(當前股票價格 埃比斯$8.48)
Yes! That's what I'm talking about.
好 就是這樣
We take care of each other.
我們互相守望
It's embedded in our DNA.
這是我們與生俱來的
Not because an equation tells us to, but because we feel it in here.
不因為等式告訴我們如此 而是因為我們心有所感
And right now, I need your help.
此刻 我需要你們的説明
This looks promising.
看來很有潛質
We can do the right thing.
我們可以做好
But we have to do it together.
但我們必須同心協力
Come on. Refresh, refresh.
加油 更新 更新
(當前股票價格 埃比斯金融公司)
(埃比斯$8.49 利說三倍買入)
So, I'm talking to every one of you.
你們每一個人
Every single person that's watching me right now.
每一個正看著我的人
I want you to dig as deep as you can
我希望你們挖得越深越好
and I want you to ask yourself, what is a life worth to you?
請你們自問 一條命對於你來說值多少錢?
What's my life worth?
我的命值多少錢?
I guess that answers that question, huh?
我想這就是問題的答案吧?
Detective, one coming in.
警探 有人來了
Ma'am. Excuse me.
女士 打擾一下
Ma'am. NYPD. You live here?
女士 我是紐約警局的 你住這裡嗎?
Yeah. What's the problem?
是呀 有事嗎?
What's your relationship to Kyle Budwell, ma'am?
你和科爾·巴德維爾是什麼關係?
Why? Where is he?
怎麼了? 他在哪裡?
Where have you been all day? If you don't mind me asking.
你一天都在哪? 若不介意我這麼問
I work in a glass box underground for eight hours a day.
我在地鐵站的商店工作 每天8小時
So could you please just tell me what the hell is going on here,
那麼請你告訴我 到底出了什麼事
because you're really starting to freak me out.
因為你真的嚇到我了
I'm gonna ask again.
我再問一次
What is your relationship to Kyle Budwell, ma'am?
你和科爾·巴德維爾什麼關係?
Why don't you take a wild guess.
你怎麼不猜一下
Powell.
朋友?
Okay, I'll clear a path.
好 我會清條路出來
I should've taken that bet after all, you sack of shit.
我真該跟你打賭 你個混球
This is really impressive, Lee.
真驚奇 利
I mean, talk about market influence.
我是說市場的影響力
(當前股票價格 埃比斯金融公司)
(埃比斯$8.27 利說三倍買入)
Do you want to know why that shit didn't work, asshole?
你知道為什麼這破招不管用嗎?
Because even you don't buy your own bullshit.
因為你不買自己的破爛
You believe in money. You don't believe in people.
你只信錢 不信人
Lee, they tracked down his girlfriend.
利 他們找到他女朋友了
They don't believe in you, either.
他們也不信你
His pregnant girlfriend.
他女朋友懷孕了
- You got to be fucking joking.  - No, no joke, Lee.
- 你他媽開玩笑吧  - 不是開玩笑 利
Quant.
分析師
Quantitative analytics.
定量分析師
Look, I have no idea what you're saying right now.
我現在聽不懂你說什麼 你們有人說英語嗎?
Does anybody there speak English?
這裡有人會說英語嗎?
Fuck.
操
I need the other number for the guy in Moscow.
我要那個莫斯科人的另一個號碼
Yeah, but he gave me another name. This one's based out of Seoul.
好 但他給了我另一個人 是首爾的
(登入用戶名萊斯特)
(登入失敗 用戶名無效)
God damn it. Goodloe.
該死的 古德洛
- Shit.  - I've got it.
我來吧
Go get me a phone number. I'm gonna find a translator.
給我電話號碼 我會去找個翻譯來
Amy! Amy! Amy!
艾米 艾米 艾米
Bring your security pass and come with me.
帶上你的職員證跟我來
Hurts, doesn't it?
心疼吧?
Got your fancy education.
得到教訓了吧
Got your millions in the bank.
銀行裡幾百萬
Think you got it all made.
以為都賺到了
You're not such a hot shit right now, huh?
你現在沒那麼紅吧?
You want to sit here and take stock of our lives, Kyle?
你想坐在這 賭上我們的性命嗎 科爾?
How about we compare scores?
我們來比比分數如何
How about we do that?
怎麼樣?
Touchscreen. Shit, the touchscreen.
觸屏 該死 他要用觸屏
All right. We got Kyle and we got Lee.
好 這邊是科爾 這邊是利
(分數板 科爾 利)
Let's start with the obvious. Money.
從最顯而易見的開始 錢
I got some. You don't, I gather.
我有 但我想你沒有
So, that's a point for me.
那我就得一分
Where you going with this, Lee?
你要幹什麼 利?
But then there's family.
但是還有家人
I'm divorced three times. What about you? You got a wife?
我離過三次婚 你呢? 有妻子嗎?
Girlfriend, then?
有女朋友嗎?
Sacajawea, Lee.
薩卡加維亞 利
You got a girlfriend? That's nice. The magic of young love.
你有女朋友? 很好 年輕人神奇的愛情
I think we can both agree that's a point for you,
我想我們倆都同意你得一分
since the first number on my speed-dial is an escort service.
因為我設置的第一個快速撥號 是個三陪小姐
- You don't know anything about me.  - I don't need to know about you!
- 你不瞭解我  - 不需要瞭解你
I know about me. Seven years, three years, 14 months.
我瞭解我自己 七年 三年 14個月
The marriages, they get shorter and they get shorter,
婚姻越來越短
but settlements, they get larger and larger.
但贍養費越來越多
Lee?
利?
Look at me, Lee.
利 看著我
Sacajawea.
薩卡加維亞
Hey, Kyle, you see her?
科爾 你看到她了嗎?
That's Patty, my director, and she wants me to shut up.
那是帕蒂 我的導演 她想讓我閉嘴
Well, now, she's sick of me, too.
她現在也很討厭我
And that's why she took a job across the street and didn't tell me.
因此她瞞著我 跳槽到街對面去
People talk.
人言可畏
They all leave sooner or later, Kyle. That's just how it works.
他們遲早都會離開 科爾 就是這樣
So trust me, that's gonna be a point for you.
所以相信我 這一分是你的
What about kids?
孩子呢?
You got a kid?
你有孩子嗎?
One on the way, maybe?
也許正懷著一個?
Yeah? She's expecting. It's a blessing.
是嗎? 她懷孕了 真幸福
I have one myself.
我自己也有個孩子
She must be six or seven. I have no idea.
她應該六七歲了 我不知道
I send a check.
我寄張支票
Mazel tov on the bundle of joy.
祝賀喜得貴子
I think we can both agree that's another fucking point for you.
我想你我都同意你他媽又得一分
So, now, look at this.
你看看吧
Kyle. Oh, my God. We just got started and you're already ahead.
科爾 天呀 我們才剛開始 你就已經領先了
Just... Just stay wide, Jim.
保持遠景鏡頭 吉姆
So let me ask you something, Kyle.
我問你 科爾
What about your life is so much shittier than the rest of ours
既然你的生活比別人的都糟
that you get to throw in the towel early?
那麼提早結束如何?
I want to know.
我想知道
You got a decent job. You got two hands and two feet.
你有個體面工作 手腳齊全
You got a goddamn kid on the way!
馬上就要有孩子了
So before you blow me to kingdom come, I want you to answer one question.
在你把我炸開花之前 我想你回答一個問題
What makes you such a giant fucking failure compared to everybody else?
為什麼跟別人比起來 你他媽如此狼狽?
You really gonna stand there in your $1,000 suit
你穿著一千美金的西裝
and compare scores with me?
還跟我比分數?
My honest job pays me $14 an hour, you cocksucker.
我老老實實工作 一個小時才賺14美金 你個混蛋
So let's start there.
從這個開始吧
You know how far $14 an hour gets you here in New York?
你知道一小時14美金 在紐約能幹什麼嗎?
You know how much of that is left after I pay my rent and all my fucking bills?
你知道付了房租和所有帳單之後還剩多少嗎?
I keep paddling as hard as I can just to stay above water.
我全力以赴維持生計
It takes everything I got!
我的一切都沒了
And that's before the kid gets here.
這發生在我孩子降生之前
How the hell am I gonna supposed to support him?
我要怎麼撫養孩子?
How am I gonna take care of him?
我要怎麼照顧他
You'll take great care of him.
你會照顧得很好
He gets to grow up being the kid whose old man blew himself up on live TV.
他會變成一個 在直播現場自爆的老爸的兒子
- God damn it, Lee.  - He's the goddamn Father of the Year!
- 該死的 利  - 他是該死的年度最佳父親
Don't you fucking say another word about my son
你他媽再敢說我兒子
or I'll end this right fucking now. You hear me?
我現在就引爆 明白嗎?
- All right.  - You hear me?
- 好吧  - 明白嗎?
You want your brains splattered all over downtown, Lee, huh?
你想讓腦漿塗一地嗎 利?
Mr. Budwell!
巴德維爾先生
Mr. Budwell.
Yeah?
幹什麼?
Mr. Budwell, please stand by.
巴德維爾先生 請等一下
Stand by for what?
等什麼?
Hi, Molly. I'm Marcus Powell. Come with me.
莫里 我是馬克斯·鮑威爾 跟我來
You think I don't know what you're doing?
你以為我不知道你要幹什麼?
I know what you're doing!
我知道你要幹什麼
Lee, we're gonna put his girlfriend onscreen so you can talk to her.
利 我們要將他女朋友放上螢幕 這樣你就能跟她對話
It's all a big stall.
這些都是想要拖延
And you're gonna keep your mouth shut until then.
在那之前 你把嘴閉上
You hear me? Sitting up there, trying to figure out
明白了嗎 你坐在那上面想辦法
how to keep me from pulling this fucking trigger.
想怎麼防止我引爆炸彈
Well, this stupid fuck's gonna make me shoot him in his head,
這個白癡要讓我打爆他的頭
and there's nothing you can do about it, lady!
你什麼也做不了 女士
Just remember our only goal is to get him to put the weapon down.
記住我們只有一個目的 就是讓他放下武器
Jerking me around all fucking day.
你他媽一整天都跟我過不去
Okay, Matty, go ahead.
好了 馬蒂 進來
- Okay.  - Get in there.
- 好  - 進去
Your 10 minutes were up a long time ago. Hey. Hey!
給你們的十分鐘早就到了
You fucking crazy? What the fuck are you doing?
你他媽瘋了? 幹什麼呢?
Kyle? Are you there?
科爾? 你聽得見嗎?
Okay, circle around, circle around so you get that girl on camera.
攝像機轉過去 這樣就能拍到那個姑娘
- Kyle? Kyle?  - Molly.
- 科爾? 科爾?  - 莫里
- Can he see me?  - Yeah, I can see you.
- 他看得到我嗎?  - 看得到
- Yeah, he can see you.  - Yeah.
- 對 他看到了  - 對
- He's not... Kyle. Kyle?  - Molly.
- 他不... 科爾 科爾?  - 莫里
Yeah, Molly, where are you?
莫里 你在哪?
- Are you here? Where is she?  - Kyle?
- 你在這嗎? 她在哪?  - 科爾?
- Is she outside?  - Can he hear me?
- 她在外面?  - 他聽得見我?
- Molly?  - Kyle.
- 莫里?  - 科爾
Yeah?
幹什麼?
What are you doing here?
你在這幹什麼?
- What am I doing here?  - Yeah.
- 我在這幹什麼?  - 對
Kyle, what are you doing here?
科爾 你在這幹什麼?
Why... I thought you were working today.
我以為你今天上班呢
God.
天呀
You are the dumbest son of a bitch on the planet, you know that?
你真是這個地球上最蠢的混蛋 你知道嗎?
They told me about the money, Kyle.
錢的事他們都告訴我了 科爾
You are so fucking stupid.
你真他媽蠢
That was everything we had.
那可是我們所有的錢呀
That was every last cent.
我們就只剩那麼多了
You are such a fucking failure, Kyle, you know that?
你真他媽沒用 科爾 你知道嗎?
You have always been such a fucking failure.
你一直都他媽這麼沒用
- You sat down in the basement all night...  - Molly, just...
- 你整晚坐在地下室裡  - 莫里...
reading your fucking books, thinking you are some kind of a smart guy, but you aren't.
看你那什麼破書 以為自己多聰明似的
You fucking aren't. And now you go and you do this?
你他媽一點都不聰明 現在又跑去幹這種事?
You blow all your mother's money like some kind of a halfwit
你像個傻子似的 揮霍了你媽所有的錢
and then you come in here with a fucking bomb?
現在又跑來這裡 還帶著個炸彈?
Turn it off, for Christ's sake!
把它關掉 看在上帝份上
You hardly even know how to use a screwdriver!
你都不知道怎麼用螺絲刀
That is how useless you are around the house!
你在家就是這麼沒用
And now you're going and you're building fucking bombs?
現在卻能自己做炸彈了?
Since when did you become such a man all of a sudden?
你什麼時候 突然這麼像男人了?
But you're not a man.
但你不是男人
- You're a bitch. That's what you are.  - Turn it off.
- 你是個婊子 你就是  - 把它關掉
You hear me, Kyle? You are a bitch.
你聽見了 科爾? 你是個婊子
You cry when we fuck, you pasty little bitch!
我們做愛時你還哭呢 你這個窩囊婊子
Get the fuck off me, motherfucker!
混蛋 你們別碰我
Don't you fucking touch her. Hey!
你們別碰她 喂
And fuck you, too, Kyle!
你去死吧 科爾
This is all your fucking fault!
全都是你的錯
Why don't you just get it over with
你怎麼不去死
and shoot yourself in the head already, you chickenshit!
斃了你自己呀 窩囊廢
Come on. Just pull the fucking trigger! Pull the fucking...
來呀 你他媽開槍呀 你他媽開...
Hey.
喂
Kyle.
科爾
Back off, guys. Back off a little bit. Give us some room. Little bit.
後退 夥計們 後退一些 給我們挪點兒地方
She's gone. You take a deep breath.
她收線了 你深呼吸一下
You keep your finger on that button.
你按開關那個手指別動
You hear me, Kyle?
明白嗎 科爾?
- Give me some sign that you're hearing me.  - I'm fucking hearing you.
- 表示下你明白了  - 我他媽明白了
Okay.
好
Okay, here we go.
好 就這樣
Let's take a seat.
我們坐下
Come on.
來吧
Come on. That's it.
來吧 好
Hey.
喂
It's hard to believe you're the calm one in the relationship.
很難相信你們這對情侶裡 你是冷靜的那個
All right.
好吧
It's okay, Kyle. We've all been there, believe me.
沒關係 科爾 我們都經歷過那個階段 相信我
Just take a minute.
你休息一下
You take your time.
慢慢來
Nobody's going anywhere.
沒人會離開
Is that him again? Is that the quant?
還是他嗎? 那個定量分析師?
Translate this exactly, Amy, all right? Tell him I need to ask him some questions
艾米 一字一句翻譯 好嗎? 告訴他我要問他幾個問題
and if he doesn't talk to me, then people are going to die.
如果他不跟我說 就會有人送命
Fine. Put her on.
好 讓她聽電話
- Put her on.  - Alright.
- 讓她聽電話  - 好的
You speak English?
你會說英語?
Listen, lady, I'm not getting mixed up in all this.
女士 你聽著 我不會趟這渾水
I was hired to design a program. My job was about data.
他們雇傭我設計程式 我的工作是處理資料
It was about math. It was about theoreticals. That's it.
是數學 是理論 僅此而已
Yes, but this glitch was still a result of a program you designed.
對 但這個故障 是你設計的程式導致的
Wrong. It's user error.
不對 是使用者的錯誤
They're only calling it a glitch because nobody understands how the algo works.
他們只說是故障 因為沒人懂演算法
And if nobody can understand the math,
若沒人能懂數學
then nobody has to explain the money.
那麼就沒人能解釋金錢
Well, that's why I'm calling you. I want to understand.
所以我才打電話找你 我想理解
Fine.
好吧
Algorithms make patterns, they don't break them.
演算法是公式 不能破壞
And this algo was designed to move in and out
這個演算法是用來
of hundreds of positions in fractions of seconds.
在短短幾秒鐘 買賣成百上千個倉位
Right.
對
What it wasn't designed to do is consume large amounts of capital,
而不是用來消化大量資金的
accumulate leveraged positions or...
或積累杠杆倉 或...
Or hold a portfolio for any extended period of time.
長時間維持投資組合
Wait. What does that mean?
等等 什麼意思?
It means
意思是說
there is no way that this algorithm
這個演算法不可能
could lose $800 million in one afternoon.
一個下午就賠八個億
It is literally a mathematical impossibility.
數學上來講 是絕對不可能的
So whatever went wrong, whatever investment went haywire,
所以無論什麼問題 無論投資如何失敗
it's not the computer's fault.
都不是電腦的錯
There's human fingerprints all over this.
全部都是人的錯
Whose fingerprints?
哪個人的錯?
Like I said, I don't want to get involved in this.
我說了 我不想被捲進去
Is there anything you can give me?
你能給我些信息嗎?
Do the math.
你自己算
You can't find your boss, and he can't find $800 million.
你找不到你老闆 你老闆也找不回來八億美金
Where did you say he was coming from?
你說他剛去完哪裡回來?
What a mess, huh?
一團亂是嗎?
I take it you've heard by now?
我想你已經聽說了?
Yeah.
對
Goodloe started calling me the second I turned my phone back on.
我剛開手機 古德洛就不停打
He and I had a disagreement over strategy.
他和我就辦事策略發生了衝突
So I heard.
我聽說了
You did good.
你做得很好
I'm proud of you... Whatever Goodloe says.
我為你自豪... 別管古德洛說什麼
Here, I got you some chocolate.
我給你買了些巧克力
From Switzerland.
瑞士的吻
Hey, I'll take those and put them in the back for you.
我幫你把行李放到車後面去
(護照 入境 南非)
That's cold.
真冷
Amy, can you sit up front, please?
艾米 請你坐前面
And don't say a fucking word.
什麼都別說
She's right. She's fucking right. She's fucking right.
她說的對 她說的對
She's fucking right!
她說的對
God damn it! Jesus.
該死 天呀
God, why do you always do this?
天 你總這樣
This isn't good, Lee.
這不好 利
You're so stupid, Kyle.
你太蠢了 科爾
You're so stupid, you stupid pussy.
你真蠢 你個蠢蛋
She's fucking right.
她說的對
Now what?
現在怎麼辦?
What the fuck am I fucking doing?
我他媽該怎麼辦?
Shit!
該死
Do not...
別...
I'll do it.
我會做
You got to fucking do it.
你要做
I got to fucking do it. You stupid piece of fucking shit.
我要做 你他媽的混蛋
What the fuck am I fucking doing? I've got to do this.
我該怎麼辦? 我馬上就做
Kyle.
科爾
What am I gonna do? Shoot you?
我該怎麼辦? 斃了你?
I don't want to shoot you, Kyle. I don't want you to die.
我不想斃了你 科爾 我不想你死
What chance do I have now?
我還能怎麼辦?
There's still a way out of this. I know there's still a way out.
還有解決辦法 我知道還有辦法
Tell me one reason why I shouldn't put this gun in my mouth
給我一個不開槍打死自己
and pull the fucking trigger.
還有不引爆炸彈的理由
Kyle, look at me.
科爾 看著我
Hey.
喂
You made a mistake.
你犯了個錯
That doesn't mean your life is over.
並不意味著你該結束生命
What you need is a plan.
你需要的是計畫
No way any plan's gonna help me through this.
沒什麼計畫能幫我度過這個難關
That's 'cause you're not thinking straight.
因為你沒好好想
I'm willing to help you if you'll let me.
我願意幫你 只要你讓我幫
Step one.
第一步
This gun and this vest is not helping anything.
這把槍和這個背心一點用都沒有
- I know what you're trying to do.  - Signals get crossed. Things get chaotic.
- 我知道你想幹什麼  - 目的達到了 事情變一團糟
Innocent people get hurt. It happens all the time.
無辜的人受傷 總是這樣
If I let any of these guys go then I'm dead.
我要是讓這些人走了 我就死定了
Jesus.
天呀
All right.
好吧
We'll find another way.
再想個別的辦法
You got to give me some space. I need to rethink this.
你容我再好好想想
Is Fox 2 in position? Make your move.
二號狐狸就位了嗎? 行動
A plan, Kyle.
計畫 科爾
That's all we need.
我們只需要計畫
We just got unobstructed access, north side studio.
我們剛到無遮擋位置 在攝影棚北邊
Repeat. Unobstructed access on the north.
重複 攝影棚北邊無遮擋位置
- Go with him. Extraction only, though.  - Sir.
- 跟他去 只進行疏散  - 好的
Do you understand? Extraction only right now.
你們明白嗎? 現在只進行疏散
(曼博情況如何?)
(曼博凍結)
Listen, I agree with you. We need to get ahead of this one.
聽著 我同意你說的 我們需要提前著手
And we're all about transparency, after all.
我是說 我們終究要公開
I'm the CEO, so I'm the one who needs to make the statement.
我是首席行政長官 所以應該我來發表聲明
We just need to make sure it's on our terms, not on theirs.
我們只需保證對我們有利 而非有利於他們
We're all set up at Federal Hall.
我們在聯邦紀念堂做準備
We have the run of the place, we have security onsite,
我們有權使用那個地方 那裡有我們的保安
and no one knows you'll be going there.
沒人知道你會去那裡
We're going in.
我們進來了
We got company.
我們有支援了
Three, show me.
三號機 讓我看看
Okay, as long as it's controlled.
好 只要能控制
Give an exclusive to somebody you trust.
給你信任的人一個獨家報導
I know just the person to call.
我知道該叫誰
That's my girl.
真是乖孩子
All right, Lenny?
蘭尼 可以嗎?
I want you to push in. Block as much of his view as you can.
你推進去一些 儘量擋住他的視線
Lee?
利?
Do not make a move.
別動
If he turns around,
他若轉身看到
we are all gonna die.
我們就都死定了
All right, Lenny.
好吧 蘭尼
You're the last manned camera.
你是最後一個攝影師
Balls.
做個漢子
Patty Fenn.
帕蒂·芬恩
Patty, Diane Lester.
帕蒂 黛安·萊斯特
You better have something for me, Diane, and I mean, right the fuck now.
你最好說些有用的 黛安 趕快
It's good to hear your voice, too.
我也很高興聽到你
I'm calling you to let you know the information I gave you
我想說之前給你的資訊
might have been incorrect.
可能不太正確
What the hell does that mean? "Incorrect"?
什麼意思? 不正確?
Walt is going to make a statement after all.
華特終究還是要發表聲明
We're in the car en route to Federal Hall right now.
我們正坐車去聯邦紀念堂
We'll be about 20 minutes away.
大約20分鐘後到
Twenty minutes? We need help right now!
20分鐘? 我們現在就需要幫助
I'm trying to help you, if you'll just listen.
我會盡力幫助你 只要你聽我說
I'm going to send you a text explaining what I need from you.
我會給你發個資訊 告訴你我需要你怎麼配合
So just keep a lid on it.
要保密
Because I'm giving you this exclusively. Don't screw it up.
因為這是只給你一個人的 別洩密
Reporters.
記者們
Hello? Diane?
喂?
Okay, everybody. We're gonna begin evacuation one at a time.
好吧各位 我們一次疏散一個人
You first. Follow me to the crawlspace.
你先出來 跟我到走廊去
We're ready and in position. Give me the green light, we go.
準備就緒 給我們指示我們就行動
If we take out the receiver on Gates' chest, what's his chance of survival?
我們若射擊蓋茲胸前的接收器 他的生還幾率多大?
80% that he makes it.
80%的可能性
Okay. What's the chance the bullet's on target?
好吧 命中目標的幾率呢?
- If it's a clean shot, 100%.  - 100%. Come on, let's be realistic here.
- 無障礙射擊 100%命中  - 100% 得了吧 現實些
I am being. Listen, 80% sounds about right to us, to an officer.
我很現實 80%還說得過去
80%.
80%
So we got an 80% chance of an 80% chance. Yeah, that's some shit math.
那我們就是80%機會中的80% 是這麼算吧
Benson, let me know when the control room is ready to evacuate.
本森 控制室清空後告訴我
(黛安·萊斯特 華特沒去日內瓦 他去了南非)
Now we're talking.
終於給了點有用的資訊
Okay, guys,
好了 各位
how do we find out what Walt Camby's jet was doing in South Africa?
我們如何能查到 華特·坎比的飛機去南非幹什麼?
- We could try the FAA.  - No, they won't help us.
- 我們可以試試聯邦航空管理局  - 不行 他們才不會幫我們
What about the hacker guy from the Citi security breach segment?
花旗銀行保安部那個駭客呢?
- The guy with the Yoda voice.  - Yes! Yes! Find him. Quickly.
- 嗓音像尤達的那個人  - 對 就是他 快點兒
Watch your head. Step here.
小心你的頭 踩這裡
Bree, where the hell is Ron Sprecher? And has he gotten to the SEC yet?
布瑞 羅恩·斯普雷徹在哪? 他到證交所了嗎?
I will check, but I need to tell you something first.
我來看看 但我要先告訴你件事
Okay, hold on. Just a second.
好 等一下
Lee, Walt Camby has landed.
利 華特·坎比降落了
He's on his way to Federal Hall.
他在去聯邦紀念堂路上
He'll be there in less than 20 minutes.
20分鐘內到
And get this. He wasn't in Geneva yesterday. He was in South Africa.
還有 他昨天沒去日內瓦 他去了南非
So he lied to you. He lied to us.
他騙了你 騙了我們
He's been lying this whole time. That means you've been lying, too, Lee.
他一直在撒謊 也就是說你也一直在撒謊 利
To everybody that's been watching. To Kyle.
騙了所有觀眾 包括科爾
Oh, my God.
操
Where'd everybody go?
大家都哪去了?
Where'd they go?
他們都去哪了?
God damn it!
該死
I knew this would happen.
我就知道會這樣
- Let's go. Who's next?  - Charlie, in the sound booth.
- 走吧 下一個是誰?  - 查理 在音效室裡
How stupid am I?
我有多傻?
Okay. Quick as you can.
好 儘快
Get those hackers working.
讓那些駭客快些
It's all your fault, Lee. You so stupid.
都是你的錯 利 你很愚蠢
(資訊已發送)
(我們被綁架了 需要你的説明)
(請立即回電 十萬火急)
This is Dave.
我是戴夫
I got your email, Dave.
我收到你的電郵了 戴夫
Help you, we will.
我們會幫你的
This is Eagle One. Target is in position.
我是鷹眼一號 目標就位
Bunch of crooks.
一群混蛋
Camby's never coming here. We have to figure out a way, Kyle.
坎比永遠不會來了 我們得想個法子 科爾
Patty, I really need to tell you something.
帕蒂 我真的有話要說
Okay, hold on, just a second, Bree.
好 等一下 布瑞
No! Damn it! You need to hear this.
不行 該死的 你必須聽我說
Okay. What is it?
好 什麼?
Don't stop. Don't panic. Stay low.
別停下 別慌 別站起來
I'm so fucked!
我死定了
- Eagle, Do you have a clean shot?  - I'm yellow. Yellow.
- 鷹眼 射程內有障礙嗎?  - 部分障礙 部分
- Are you sure?  - Positive.
- 真的?  - 真的
They're going to shoot Lee. I heard every word. I was five-feet away.
他們要對利射擊 我距離他們只有一米半 都聽到了
Let's go. This isn't voluntary.
不管你願不願意
- Grab whatever you can grab.  - Jim. Take Jim.
- 收拾東西  - 讓吉姆走
- Let's go.  - Be careful.
- 走吧  - 小心
I can't catch a fucking break.
我倒楣透了
I'm never getting out of here. Fuck!
我永遠也出不去了 操
Lee.
利
They're making us leave.
他們在疏散我們
- Don't stop. It's gonna be fine.  - I'm good. Get Patty.
- 不要停下 別怕  - 我沒事 讓帕蒂走
Look at me.
看著我
Don't look up. Look at me.
別看上面 看我
There is a sniper on the catwalk at your one o'clock.
走廊上有個狙擊手 就在你現在1點鐘位置
Where'd they fucking go?
他們幹什麼呢?
He's about to lose it, Benson.
他要鬆開關了 本森
- Hold on. I got one lagging.  - Benson, hurry the hell up!
- 等等 有個人不配合  - 快點兒走
There is a receiver on your vest.
你背心上有個接收器
- Two seconds, I pull out my cuffs.  - Don't look down.
- 再等兩秒鐘我就用手銬了  - 別看下麵
If he shoots it out, it disables the trigger.
如果他射中了 就能讓引爆開關失靈
Get out of there, right now!
快走 快
Come on!
走吧
- You got a shot?  - Are you green or red?
- 射程有障礙嗎?  - 有沒有?
- Green.  - Take the shot!
- 沒有  - 開槍
- What are you doing? What are you doing?  - Fuck!
你幹什麼? 你幹什麼?
The button!
開關 開關
- Are you all right?  - What the fuck?
- 你沒事吧?  - 什麼鬼?
They're shooting at me, not you! God damn it!
他們是對我開槍 不是你 混蛋
Just keep your finger on the button.
按住開關別動
Lee, can you hear me?
利 聽得到嗎?
What is this? You been talking to the cops this whole time?
這是什麼? 你一直在跟員警聯絡?
That's Patty.
是帕蒂
Listen to me!
聽我說
She found Walt Camby.
她找到華特·坎比了
I'm gonna take you to him. But you got to trust me.
我會帶你去見他 但你要相信我
I got a plan.
我有主意了
Listen, you got to block my vest.
聽著你要擋住我的背心
Go.
走
- Hey, wait. What are we doing?  - We're getting out of here.
- 等等 幹什麼?  - 離開這裡
Give me the mike.
給我話筒
Are you setting me up?
你這是陷害我嗎?
You want some answers? We're gonna get some answers.
你想要個說法嗎? 我們就去討個說法
Lenny, you coming?
蘭尼 你來嗎?
We're coming out!
我們出來啦
(錄影中)
Lenny.
蘭尼
You mind?
你不介意吧?
Balls.
漢子
Holy shit.
該死
- What's the matter with you?  - I don't like elevators.
- 你怎麼了?  - 我不喜歡搭電梯
Come on, Lenny.
拜託 蘭尼
Lenny, where are you?
蘭尼 你在哪?
What did I ever do to deserve such a loyal goddamn crew, Lenny?
我做了什麼好事 配得上這麼衷心的員工?
- Not much.  - That's right.
- 沒幹什麼好事  - 對
I need a satellite van and an audio package downstairs in two minutes.
兩分鐘後 給我準備一輛衛星車和音效設備
Lenny, where are you?
蘭尼 你在哪?
Jim, where's my feed with Lenny? I need it right now.
吉姆 蘭尼拍的鏡頭呢? 馬上給我放出來
Come on, Lenny.
拜託 蘭尼
Patty tells us to stay, we stay.
帕蒂讓我們留下 我們就留下
Okay, Lenny's up! He's live.
好了 蘭尼的攝像機出現了 他在直播
Yeah, Patty. It's always Patty.
對 帕蒂 總是帕蒂
My first day on the job she told me I had a penis where my brain should be.
我上班第一天她就告訴我 我沒腦子
She's right. She's always right.
她說的對 從來都是對的
She stayed here longer than she should have.
她不需要留在這裡這麼久
I know that.
我知道
The truth is I don't know what I'd do without her at this point.
事實是我不知道 要是沒有她我可怎麼辦
But if she was standing right here, right now, I couldn't admit that.
但若她此刻站在這裡 我就說不出這些話
But luckily it's just you in front of me, Lenny. You and your...
但有幸只有你在我跟前 蘭尼 你和你的...
Your warm eyes and your gentle soul.
你的溫柔眼神和溫順人格
All right, get the fuck out of here.
好啦 快他媽離開這裡
- I got a signal.  - Okay, are we live?
- 我收到信號了  - 好吧 我們是直播嗎?
Time to find Diane Lester. Let's go.
該去找黛安·萊斯特了 走吧
- If you're still with us, here we go.  - Come on.
你若還在看 我們出發了
- We're going that way, Lenny. That way.  - Okay.
- 走那邊 蘭尼 那邊  - 好
- Captain.  - No.
- 警監  - 不
We're on the move. Clear a path.
移動中 清路
- That van comes with us!  - Clear the sat van.
- 那輛車跟我們走  - 清空那輛車
What are these people doing here?
這麼多人在幹什麼?
Now they've left the building.
他們已經離開大樓了
They are taking to the streets.
他們走街上
Kyle Budwell and host Lee Gates seem to be working together at this point.
財經有線電視人質危機 《金錢怪獸》行動起來
(科爾·巴德維爾和利·蓋茲 現在似乎在合作)
Hello?
喂?
We're on our way to you now, but we need something more.
我們正在去你們那邊 但我們需要更多消息
We've figured out where, we need to find out why.
我們知道他去了哪兒 但我們還需要知道為什麼
He's been lying about everything.
他一直都在撒謊
Keep him away from the news until we figure out the connection.
別讓他看新聞 等我們查出原因再說
I understand.
明白了
Here. You should put your suit on.
給你 換上西裝
I'll come back up for you once they're all set up.
他們準備好之後我會回來接你
Thanks.
謝謝
Jim, throw the feed into my sat van.
吉姆 把畫面放到我的衛星轉播車上
You stay with Lenny on foot. We're gonna go nat sound from his camera.
你跟蘭尼步行過去 我們會從他的攝像機收聲音
Where the hell is Ron Sprecher?
羅恩·斯普雷徹在哪?
Patty! I just left the SEC. I've been trying to call you.
帕蒂 我剛離開證交所 我一直在試著打你電話
Yeah, Ron, listen.
羅恩 聽著
- Yeah, they got nothing over here.  - What?
- 他們什麼都沒有  - 什麼?
Ibis's algorithm trades in dark pools,
埃比斯的演算法是黑市交易
so all their transactions are concealed.
所以他們所有資金往來 都是秘密進行的
The one thing I was able to find out was, on the day of the crash,
我只查到一件事 就是出事那天
Ibis's transaction volume
埃比斯的交易量
dropped by nearly 90%.
驟降90%
What does that mean?
這是什麼意思?
I don't know.
我不知道
How far away are you?
你離我們多遠?
I'm on... Where am I? I'm on Vesey Street.
我... 我在哪? 我在維西街
Bring me what you have, Ron. I'll meet you at the corner of Pearl and Pine.
把你的發現給我送來 羅恩 我在珠寶街和青松道交口等你
Start running. I'll see you in three minutes.
跑過來 三分鐘後見
What, three minutes? That's a half-mile away! I can't run a half-mile in three...
三分鐘? 有一公里呀 我不可能三分鐘跑一公...
Hello?
喂?
What are you folks doing?
你們這些人都在幹什麼?
He's not O.J.! Get off the street! That's a bomb!
他不是明星殺人犯OJ辛普森 快離開街道 那可是炸彈呀
Bombs explode.
炸彈會爆炸
You don't want to be near them when they do.
爆炸時別靠近
Frank Ross, reporting from the eye in the sky.
我是弗蘭克羅斯 空中攝像正在直播
He is safely hovering above them.
安全地盤旋在他們上空
(利·蓋茲和科爾·巴德維爾 他們要去哪?)
It's a rather distressing scene down here, honestly.
說實話 這一鏡頭很令人不安
New Yorkers flocking to the melee despite repeated police warnings
紐約市民紛紛湧上街頭 不顧員警的警告
to stay clear of the path of a man with a bomb strapped to his chest.
不要靠近這個胸前有炸彈的人
Apparently, a lot of people sharing the feelings
顯然很多人都很同情
of gunman Kyle Budwell this moment.
科爾·巴德維爾...
They are lining the streets, they're cheering him on, as if to say,
他們在街道兩旁 給他喝彩 似乎在說
"Hey, Ibis, show us the money."
"喂 埃比斯 告訴我們錢去哪了"
They're a bunch of crooks! Blow 'em all to hell!
他們是一幫混蛋 把他們炸開花
Get off me, man! Come on!
放開我 求你了
Stay close. Don't let them get a shot at the vest.
靠近我 別讓他們對背心開槍
Now might be a good time to tell you something about that vest then.
我想該告訴你 那件背心的事了
There's not actually any Semtex in there. It's just clay. Blocks of clay.
根本不是什麼森泰克斯炸藥 只是粘土 粘土磚
What?
什麼?
Yeah, I wanted to get your attention, not blow up a goddamn building.
對 我只是想博取注意力 不是真想炸掉大樓
Stand down. Easy.
立定 別緊張
Well, they think it's real.
他們認為是真的
So whatever you do, don't take your finger off that goddamn trigger.
無論如何 你別鬆開關
We're in this together, you dumb shit.
我們現在共同進退 你個混蛋
The drama featuring host Lee Gates and Kyle Budwell.
事件主角 利·蓋茲和科爾·巴德維爾
Wow, this is getting crazy!
哇 越來越瘋狂了
Look at all these people!
看看那些人群
My phone is blowing up on this.
我電話都被這事刷屏了
If Kyle makes it out of this thing, we got to get him on the show.
若科爾被釋放 我們一定要請他來做嘉賓
And the next time I have a bad day, I'm gonna come in, "Glitch!"
下次我不順心時 我會喊"故障"
Diane, why would Ibis's trading volume suddenly drop 90%?
黛安 埃比斯交易量為何驟降90%?
90%?
No, that's not possible. Ibis's algorithms trade continuously.
不可能 埃比斯的演算法是持續交易的
Somebody would have had to have taken the computers offline.
一定是某人切斷電腦連接
They would have...
他們會...
Human fingerprints.
人為失誤
Walt.
華特
If Walt took that $800 million away from the algorithm,
若華特從演算法拿走了那八億美金
what did he do with it?
他會拿那筆錢做什麼?
I have his phone. Shit.
我有他的手機 該死
He's deleted all his emails.
他把郵件都刪除了
Try texts.
試試信息
Goodloe.
古德洛
Mambo... Mambo...
曼博... 曼博...
He and the COO keep mentioning "Mambo" over and over again.
他和首席運營官不斷提到"曼博"
"Mambo"?
"曼博"?
Mambo, like the dance?
曼博舞嗎?
"Mambo"?
"曼博"?
Hey! Hey!
喂
Get out of the way! Hey!
別擋著路 喂
Get out of the way!
快走開
Patty!
帕蒂
- We're on it, Diane.  - Stop. Stop. Stop. Patty.
- 我們來查 黛安  - 停車 帕蒂
Get this earpiece to Lee. He needs to hear me.
把這個耳機給利 他得聽我說話
Great. But how exactly am I supposed to get this to him?
行呀 但我該怎麼給他呀
I don't know, Ron. You're a producer. Produce your way up there!
我不知道 羅恩 你是製作人 製作個方法出來
I'm not getting anything on the terminal. I'm gonna do a web search.
我用終端機什麼都查不到 我要上網查
Okay, I'm getting...
好 有了...
"Mambo Pizza Place..."
"曼博比薩店..."
"Mambo Italiano..." I'm not finding anything.
"義大利曼博... "什麼都找不到
"Mambo Snakes."
"曼博蛇"
"Mamba" snakes. That's not it.
曼博蛇 不對
Try "Mambo South Africa." Try anything South African.
試試"南非曼博" 所有南非的東西
Got it. One sec.
明白 等一下
(南非曼博)
Holy shit.
該死
(曼博領導礦工罷工)
It's not a program. It's a goddamn person.
不是電腦程式 是個人名
Remember Zuccotti Park!
別忘了祖科蒂公園
Occupy Wall Street!
佔領華爾街
Hey, Lee! Lee!
利 利
Hey!
嘿
Lee!
利
Do it, man! Come on. Blow this mother up!
炸了他 拜託 炸了那個混蛋
Lee! Lee, hey! Lee! Your earpiece!
利 你的耳機
- Shit.  - Ron!
羅恩
Do not shoot!
別開槍
Lee, can you hear me?
利 聽得見嗎?
Camera mike's down. He's not gonna be able to respond.
攝像機的話筒壞了 他沒法回應
Sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
對不起 對不起
Lee?
利?
Lee, are you there? If you can hear me, put your hand in the air.
利 你在嗎? 你若能聽到就舉手
Okay. I can see you, but I can't get to you.
好 我能看到你 但我過不去
What am I gonna do?
我該怎麼辦?
We either keep going or we stop. It's up to you.
我們可以繼續走 也可以就此結束 你決定
ESU, forward.
緊急事件小組 前進
First window we get, we're taking the assailant down.
一旦有空隙 我們就擊斃這個混蛋
Move them back.
讓他們退下
(員警 炸彈分隊)
- Stay down.  - Stay behind the car.
- 蹲下  - 躲在車後面
Diane, are you still there?
黛安 你在聽嗎?
Yeah, I'm here.
是的 我在
Okay. We are on Mambo.
好 我們在查曼博
Our van can't get any closer.
我們的車不能靠近了
So keep Walt there.
讓華特待在那
Do not let him run before Lee can get to you.
利到達之前 別讓他跑了
Okay, I'll see what I can do.
好 我盡力
All right. Get on it, Dave.
好的 繼續查 戴夫
Print out everything you can on this miners' strike.
把所有關於罷工的東西都列印出來
- I'm gonna need that, too.  - Okay.
- 我也需要  - 好
Lee?
利?
You can hear me now.
你現在能聽到我了
Which is good.
很好
I have a lot to explain,
我要解釋很多東西
and I need you to listen very carefully for once.
你得仔細聽我說
We're approaching Federal Hall.
我們要去聯邦紀念堂
Jesus. Is that live?
天呀 是直播嗎?
It is now.
就是現在
Did you get all that? And that's before we start digging.
你都明白嗎? 那是我們開始調查之前
- Ibis is a pig in a prom dress, Lee.  - Got it.
- 埃比斯是個穿著裙子的豬 利  - 明白
We are trying to find the proof right now.
我們現在努力找證據
See if you can get those hacker guys. Find out what they've come up with.
看你能否聯繫到那些駭客 看他們能發現什麼
Now, Lee, we're making a pretty big leap here.
利 我們現在有很大進展
So if Walt's gonna hang himself, you're gonna have to hand him that rope.
若華特想上吊 你要給他繩子
I'll just point the camera in your direction, and we'll figure it out together.
我會讓攝像機對準你 我們一起來想辦法
Hey. Get ready for a show.
好 準備表演
Well, these guys are certainly behaving
這些人現在的行為好像
like they've got an appointment with the Ibis Clear Capital CEO.
他們和埃比斯金融公司首席行政長官 約好了要見面
Which begs the question on everyone's mind,
這令大家都很好奇
where is Walt Camby?
華特·坎比在哪?
As a curious crowd assembles outside Federal Hall,
聯邦紀念堂外聚集了一群人
the missing piece of the puzzle...
現在缺失的那塊拼圖是...
I trusted you.
我是信任你的
Yeah, well, I trusted you, too.
對 我也信任過你
So I guess that means we're both wrong.
這麼說我們都錯了
What did you do, Diane? I mean, you know me.
你幹了什麼 黛安? 你瞭解我的
You know me better than my wife.
你比我妻子更瞭解我
- You know me better than anybody.  - I'm not so sure that's true.
- 你比任何人都瞭解我  - 我可不知道
I have no idea what you think I did.
我不知道你以為我做了什麼
Save it for the cameras, Walt.
留著對攝像機說吧 華特
An eyewitness in the crowd may just have the answer.
或許人群中的目擊者 能告訴我們答案
Walt Camby?
華特·坎比?
He's inside. He just went up those stairs and through those doors.
他就在裡面 他剛從這裡上臺階走進去
- You saw him?  - That's right.
- 你看到他了?  - 對
Guess there's nowhere to run now, huh?
我猜無處可逃了吧?
This story does seem to be coming to some sort of head down here.
看來事件將轉移到這裡
- Hey there, big shot.  - Hey.
- 喂 大咖  - 喂
- Ready for that interview now?  - Hey.
- 準備好接受採訪了嗎?  - 喂
Hey.
喂
You're just in time for the show.
你正好趕上節目播出
How was Geneva?
日內瓦如何?
- It was fine.  - Yeah, I hear it's lovely this time of year.
- 不錯  - 是嗎 我聽說今年這個時候挺好
Can we get him a chair?
能給他椅子嗎?
Sam, give him a chair.
山姆 給他把椅子
The Iceland guys just came through with all the facial recognition data.
冰島的人剛給我些面部識別資料
This footage goes back months.
是近幾個月的原始錄影
Everywhere he's traveled. There's way too much stuff.
他去過的所有地方 信息量太大了
Okay, well, just focus on the last 48 hours. And cue up the video package.
好吧 只看最近48小時 把視頻調出來
Can we get everybody outta here? Young lady, please, exit the building.
可以請大家都出去嗎? 那位小姐 請離開大樓
Wait a second, why does she get to leave?
等一下 為什麼她能離開
This might be able to help with your investigation.
這個也許能幫助你們調查
This is all her fault.
都是她的錯
Go ahead, Diane, walk away.
你走吧 黛安
You're the only reason we're stuck here with this psycho.
都是因為你 我們才和這個瘋子困在一起
You wanted transparency, Walt? Well, here's your chance.
你想要公開嗎 華特? 你的機會來了
Let's go.
走吧
Everybody hates you.
大家都恨你
Okay, now look, everything is fine.
好吧 聽著 沒事了
So why don't we just put the weapons down, and let's just talk about it.
不如放下武器 好好談談
No, I... I think we can talk with the weapons up. Right, guys?
不... 我想我們可以拿著武器談 是吧 各位?
- This is Money Monster, coming to you live.  - Back off.
- 這裡是《金錢怪獸》現場直播  - 後退
We're here with Ibis CEO Walt Camby.
埃比斯首席行政長官華特·坎比就在這裡
So, Walt, now that we have you here in person,
華特 既然你親自到場
we can finally ask the $800 million question.
我們終於可以問問那八億美金的事了
What happened at Ibis, Walt?
埃比斯出了什麼事 華特?
As we've been saying since day one, this was an isolated computer glitch.
我們從第一天就開始說 那是孤立電腦故障事件
Goddamn it!
該死
- Glitch!  - He doesn't really like that word.
- 故障  - 他不喜歡那個詞
I fuckin' hate that word!
我他媽恨死這個詞了
Not the glitch.
不是故障
- Cue up video one.  - I fucking hate that word.
- 放視頻一  - 我他媽討厭這個詞
And then line the rest of 'em up on my mark.
然後聽我指示依次放其他視頻
You tried to convince us it's all too complicated for us to understand.
你想叫我們相信 事情太複雜我們不會理解的
But it's not that complicated at all, is it?
但根本沒那麼複雜吧?
It's actually the oldest story in the book. Fraud.
其實就是老把戲 詐騙
You took money out of your fund and you invested it here.
你從你的基金拿錢出來 投資到這裡
Go.
放
Right here in platinum mines in South Africa. Does that sound familiar?
就在南非的鉑金礦 聽著耳熟嗎?
I don't have our portfolio in front of me. I can't exactly...
我現在沒有我們的投資組合 我無法準確地...
You really need your portfolio to know where you put $800 million?
你真需要看投資組合檔案 才知道那八億去哪了?
I don't put that much money anywhere.
那錢我哪都沒放
The algorithms control our day-to-day...
是演算法控制日常的...
But that's not how high-frequency trading is supposed to work, is it?
但高頻率交易不該這樣做吧?
They don't just put that much money in one place
他們不會把這麼多錢放在一個地方
and just leave it there, do they?
然後就不管了吧?
It wasn't the algos pullin' the strings, it was you.
不是演算法的責任 是你
The miners' union strike here outside Johannesburg is on its second week.
約翰尼斯堡的礦工工會罷工進入第二周
You. You bought and paid for a two-week strike.
你 是你出錢進行的兩周罷工
Come on. This is ridiculous.
得了吧 這太荒唐了
Go.
放
The strike had caused the mining company's stock to drop.
罷工導致礦公司股票價格下跌
You buy low, you get the strike to stop, you sell high.
你低價買進 讓罷工停止 然後就高價賣出
That's the plan.
這就是你的計畫
You make one big bribe to the right guy, line your own pockets,
你找了個合適的人賄賂 錢進自己口袋
and no one'll be the wiser.
沒人比你更聰明
You're making accusations that have no basis in reality.
你這是毫無根據的指責
Video three on my mark.
準備視頻三
- All right, all right, all right. One...  - Get it together.
- 好的 好的 等...  - 快點兒
- Okay, it's there. Got it.  - It's defamation, okay?
- 好了 行了  - 這是誹謗 好嗎?
And there are laws about that.
誹謗是犯法的
Go on, Walt. Tell me about all the laws I'm breaking.
繼續 華特 說我犯了什麼法
Ready when you are, Lee. On your mark.
準備好了 利 等你的指示
Look, I'll give you this.
我給你看看這個
There really was a glitch in your system. It just wasn't the computer.
你的系統裡的確出了故障 但不是電腦
It was this guy. Moshe Mambo.
是這個人 摩西·曼博
We must say no!
我們必須決絕
We must say no to their businesses! We must say no to their bribes!
我們必須拒絕他們的交易 我們必須拒絕他們的賄賂
You tried to bribe the one guy that couldn't be bought.
你想賄賂這個人 但他不買帳
All they care about is money!
他們只在乎錢
If it takes two years, if it takes 20 years,
就算需要兩年 就算20年
we will stay here and strike until our voices are heard.
我們都會繼續罷工 直到我們受到關注
Pause.
暫停
There. Right there. That's your glitch.
就這裡 這是你說的故障
Because that's what sent the mining company's stock plummeting,
因為這導致了礦公司的股票暴跌
which sent your secret $800 million investment
讓你的八個億投資
right into the toilet.
付諸流水
Want me to keep goin'?
還要我繼續嗎?
- Patty. You gotta see this.  - You made people a lot of money, Walt.
- 帕蒂 你得看看這個  - 你讓大家賺了很多錢 華特
You just needed to wreck industries and destroy economies all over the world to do it.
你只需要毀了產業和世界各地的經濟...
Okay. Get that ready right now. Lee?
好 馬上準備好 利?
You're gonna say everything I say.
你重複我說的話
This is insane.
這太瘋狂了
I don't know the first thing about some South African workers' strike.
我不知道什麼南非工人罷工
I've never even heard of this Mambo.
我都沒聽過曼博這個人
- Really? Never?  - Really? Never?
- 真的? 從沒聽過?  - 真的? 從沒聽過?
Well, what were you two arguing about this morning?
那你們兩個今天上午在吵什麼?
Then what were you two arguing about this morning
at 8:02 a.m., local time?
在當地時間8點02分?
Or maybe they're speaking Swahili in Geneva these days.
或者也許日內瓦如今 開始說斯瓦希裡語了
They don't speak Swahili in South Africa, either.
南非也不說斯瓦希裡語
And this wasn't the first time you did it, either.
你這不是第一次了
This was just the first time it didn't work out.
只不過是第一次不奏效而已
You feel that, Walt?
你感覺到了嗎 華特?
That sticky heat risin' up the back of your neck?
脖梗子發熱?
That flop sweat?
出汗了?
That's fear.
這就是恐懼
Greed you're already acquainted with.
你熟悉的貪婪
That's all a great story, Lee. I'm actually sorry the real one's so boring.
這故事真好 利 我真的很抱歉事實卻很無聊
But the truth is, our computational systems are far too...
事實是 我們的計算系統至今為止...
You know, forget it. Just shoot him.
別管了 一槍斃了他
Actually, I got a better idea.
事實上我有個更好的點子
Up. Up, up, up.
站起來
Take the vest off. Put it on him.
把背心脫了 給他穿上
Yeah? Go ahead.
行嗎? 動手
Hold on. That's just gonna make things worse.
等等 這只會令事情更糟
I already told you, back off.
我說過了 你後退
Fuckin' cops.
該死的員警
- Lenny.  - All right.
- 蘭尼  - 好吧
- Now? Okay.  - Just right here.
- 現在? 好  - 站這
Listen, I'm gonna do you a solid. And trust me on this.
聽著 我都按你說的做 你相信我
Don't turn your back on anybody.
別背對著任何人
You're a thief, Walt.
你是小偷 華特
And a crook.
是騙子
And I want to hear you admit it.
我要聽你承認
I didn't steal a dime,
我一分錢都沒偷
- and we didn't do anything illegal.  - Bullshit!
- 我們沒做任何犯法的事  - 胡說
- You manipulated stock prices.  - You don't care what I'm gonna say.
- 你操縱股票價格  - 你不在乎我要說什麼
- You bribed people.  - You need someone to blame.
- 你賄賂  - 你要找人怪罪
- You broke the law.  - You've already decided it's gonna be me.
- 你犯了法  - 你已經決定是我
What law? Name one law you can prove I broke.
什麼法? 說一條你能證明我違犯了的法
No, don't look at him. He can't prove it, either.
不 別看著他 他也證明不了
This is just business. And this is how business is done.
這是買賣而已 買賣就是這樣做的
- That doesn't make it right.  - Please.
- 這沒道理  - 拜託
Tell that to the Chinese.
跟中國人說去
Tell that to the Russians. 'Cause if it's not us, it's gonna be them.
跟俄國人說去 因為若不是我們 就是他們
Hell, it already is.
已經如此了
You see, that's the irony about all this.
你看 就是這麼諷刺
You only came after me 'cause I lost you money.
你只知道找我算帳 因為我讓你吃虧了
Nobody was asking questions when everybody was makin' a profit.
大家賺錢的時候就沒人提問
You just gobbled up every dollar of stock you could afford.
只會投入每一分能負擔的錢
As long as we kept paying you 18% ROI every year,
只要我們保持每年18%的回報率
then you could keep bragging to your friends about what a genius you are.
你們就會向朋友們炫耀自己是多麼天才
But, hey, you're not a genius,
但你不是天才
you're a stockholder.
你是個投資者而已
I told you what I want.
告訴你我想要什麼
Yeah, I get it. You want a profit. That's what everybody wants.
我知道 你想要利潤 所有人都想
- No, that's not what I want.  - Listen, just give us some time.
- 這不是我想要的  - 聽著 給我們些時間
We're gonna make every single dime...
我們會賺回來...
I want to hear you admit it, you son of a bitch!
我想聽你承認 混蛋
I think he just did.
我想他承認了
No, I want to hear him say that he lied, that what he did was wrong.
不 我要聽他說自己撒了謊 說他做錯了
Wrong? What does that even mean, wrong?
錯? 什麼叫錯?
You got three seconds till I blow your ass outta this goddamn building.
給你三秒鐘 否則我把你屁股炸開花
- Three.  - What's wrong with makin' a profit?
- 三  - 賺錢有什麼錯?
- What's wrong with being faster...  - Two!
- 賺得快有什麼錯...  - 二
What's wrong with betting big? Winning isn't wrong...
賭大些有什麼錯? 贏錢沒錯...
- One!  - Fine!
- 一  - 好
It was wrong.
我錯了
- It was wrong.  - Oh, my...
- 我錯了  - 哦 天...
It was wrong.
我錯了
That's all I wanted to hear, man.
這就是我想聽的
- Did you hear that?  - Nice.
- 聽到了嗎?  - 厲害
Kyle, don't.
科爾 別
- Kyle, don't!  - No! Fuck! Don't!
- 科爾 別  - 不 操 別
- God! Kyle, no!  - Stand down!
- 天呀 科爾 別  - 離開
- Goddamn it!  - I said stand down!
- 該死的  - 快離開
- Get his gun!  - I said stand down!
- 拿下他的槍  - 快離開
- Hey!  - Call an ambulance!
- 喂  - 叫救護車
- Shots fired. Repeat, we've got shots fired.  - Oh, my God.
- 開槍了 重複 我們開槍了  - 天呐
What are you doin' to him? Get him an ambulance!
你對他做了什麼? 給他叫救護車
Get him an ambulance! Get him an ambulance!
給他叫救護車
- Hey, hey, hey!  - Get off! What are you...
- 喂  - 放開我 你們...
- Room is secure!  - He can't breathe!
- 室內安全  - 他不能呼吸
- Hey!  - What are you doin' to him?
- 喂  - 你在對他做什麼?
Get him an ambulance!
給他叫救護車
Hey, Kyle, you hang in there, buddy!
科爾 堅持住 夥計
Kyle!
科爾
You hang in there, buddy.
堅持住 夥計
- You're good to go, pal.  - Yeah.
- 你可以走了  - 是的
You're all set.
沒事了
That kid's a nutcase.
那孩子瘋了
You son of a bitch.
混蛋
Hey, all right.
好啦
- Just sit down.  - You see that? He just assaulted me.
- 坐下來  - 你看到了? 他侮辱我
Call a cop.
叫員警
You got a pulse?
還有脈搏嗎?
You got anything?
有嗎?
No, sir.
沒有
Oh, my God.
天呐
They shot him. Did you see that?
他們殺了他 看見了嗎?
Clear for the coroner.
給驗屍官讓路
Copy that.
收到
This is Powell. He's been taken out.
我是鮑威爾 他被擊斃了
Called at 3:58 p.m.
3點58分擊斃
Clear it. Studio has control.
清場 攝影棚來接管
(現場直播)
Excuse me, sir. A quick question.
打擾一下 問您一個小問題
You had the chance to leave. Why did you stay?
您本來有機會離開的 為何留下?
(財經有線電視危機解除 持槍者被擊斃)
I was just... I was just doin' my job.
我只是... 只是在做本職工作
You know, I don't quit until the director tells me to.
沒有導演的命令我不會停工
Your name is?
您叫什麼名字?
My name is Lenny Libatino. It's... it's L-E-N-N-Y, not... Not the I-E.
我叫蘭尼·裡巴蒂諾 是"蘭花"的"蘭"
When did you know you were in danger?
您何時意識到身處險境?
I think right from the gunshot, you know,
我想從第一次槍響吧
but, like I said, I was more interested in keeping him in the frame.
但我說過 我更想一直拍他
Maybe I should have got hair and makeup for Lenny, huh?
也許我該給蘭尼做頭髮 化妝 是吧?
Host Lee Gates is recuperating in a downtown hospital,
主持人利·蓋茲 在市中心的醫院接受治療
along with wounded producer Ron Sprecher. He is expected to make a full recovery.
與受傷的製片人羅恩·斯普雷徹一起 他有希望完全恢復健康
How's Ron?
羅恩怎麼樣?
He's out of surgery, he's in recovery. He's gonna be fine.
他手術完成了 正在康復 他會沒事的
Good.
好
- What do you got there?  - Dinner.
- 你買了什麼?  - 晚餐
I heard you had an opening in your schedule.
我聽說你有空
So this is a Friday night for you, huh?
所以這就是你的週五夜晚吧?
Yep.
對
thanks to this single individual. Back to you, Sherry.
幸虧有這個人 報導就這麼多 雪麗
The gunman's name is Kyle Budwell,
持槍者名叫科爾·巴德維爾
24 years old, a parcel truck driver from Queens, New York.
24歲 紐約昆士蘭的運貨司機
Further details about him are still unknown at this hour, as are concrete motives.
目前尚不清楚其他細節 包括他的實際作案動機
But it's been reported that personal financial troubles,
但據報導說 個人財政困難
coupled with his mother's death six months ago,
加上六個月前他母親去世
could have been contributing factors.
可能是導致此事件的動機
And regulators are saying, "Not so fast, Walt Camby."
調控者會說 "別太快 華特·坎比"
The SEC just announced that Ibis Clear Capital
證交所剛剛宣佈 埃比斯金融公司
is facing a Foreign Corrupt Practices Act investigation.
將因涉嫌違反《反國外行賄法規》而面臨調查
(埃比斯金融公司面臨調查)
Violations of that act can carry heavy criminal and civil penalties.
違反此法規屬於嚴重犯罪並面臨民事處罰
Meanwhile, Vines of Ibis's CEO Walt Camby
同時 埃比斯首席行政長官華特·坎比
have quickly become an online phenomenon,
在網上迅速走紅
variations of which have already racked up over 10 million views online.
事件改編的視頻 已有超過一千萬人次觀看
No! No! Fuck!
不 不 操
Sherry Benedict, thank you for that report.
謝謝雪麗本內特的報導
We'll come back to you later in the day as more information emerges.
稍後將為您帶來更多新聞
So what the hell kind of show are we gonna do next week?
下周該做什麼節目呢?
Things aren't all bad for the Money Monster host,
《金錢怪獸》並非沒有好事
as viewership of Money Monster, which had recently slid in the ratings,
正當《金錢怪獸》收視率大幅下滑時
skyrocketed after word of the hostage crisis spread.
隨著人質事件廣傳 收視率飄升
Lee Gates may owe that gunman a debt of thanks.
利·蓋茲也許欠了持槍者一個天大的人情
Well, it may have been an eventful afternoon
今天下午在證券交易所外
outside the actual Stock Exchange,
或許很熱鬧
but it was a rather pedestrian day inside. The Dow was down nine points, less than...
但交易所內卻乏善可陳 道鐘斯指數下跌9個百分點...
NASDAQ dropped 13 points, thanks to a shaky morning in the tech sector.
由於科技股今早的波動 道指下降13點
Wall Street is a casino. They're gambling with your money.
華爾街是個大賭場 他們在用你的錢賭博
Your company was called "a great vampire squid wrapped around the face of humanity."
你的公司被稱為 "人性的臉上纏著的吸血鬼烏賊"
He found his fame on YouTube, of all places.
他在YouTube上出了名 紅遍世界各地